[
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the BEST preventive control to protect the confidentiality of data on a corporate smartphone in the event it is lost?",
    "options": [
      "Biometric authentication for the device",
      "Remote data wipe program",
      "Encryption of the data stored on the device",
      "Password for device authentication"
    ],
    "correct": "Encryption of the data stored on the device"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is MOST useful for determining whether the goals of IT are aligned with the organization's goals?",
    "options": [
      "Key performance indicators (KPIs)",
      "Balanced scorecard",
      "Enterprise architecture (EA)",
      "Enterprise dashboard"
    ],
    "correct": "Enterprise architecture (EA)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Capacity management tools are PRIMARILY used to ensure that",
    "options": [
      "computer systems are used to their maximum capacity most of the time",
      "concurrent use by a large number of users is enabled",
      "available resources are used efficiently and effectively",
      "proposed hardware acquisitions meet capacity requirements"
    ],
    "correct": "available resources are used efficiently and effectively"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following cloud capabilities BEST enables an organization to meet unexpectedly high service demand?",
    "options": [
      "Scalability",
      "Flexibility",
      "Alternate routing",
      "High availability"
    ],
    "correct": "Scalability"
  },
  {
    "question": "An IS auditor is reviewing an artificial intelligence (Al) and expert system application The system has produced several critical errors with severe impact Which of the following should the IS auditor do NEXT to understand the cause of the errors?",
    "options": [
      "Understand the purpose and functionality of the system.",
      "Verify system adherence to corporate policy.",
      "Review the decision-making logic built into the system.",
      "Interview the system owner"
    ],
    "correct": "Understand the purpose and functionality of the system."
  },
  {
    "question": "During the course of fieldwork, an internal IS auditor observes a critical vulnerability within a newly deployed application What is the auditor's BEST course of action?",
    "options": [
      "Report the finding to the external auditors",
      "Identify other potential vulnerabilities",
      "Notify IT management",
      "Document the finding in the report"
    ],
    "correct": "Identify other potential vulnerabilities"
  },
  {
    "question": "What should be the PRIMARY focus during a review of a business process improvement project?",
    "options": [
      "The cost of new controls",
      "Business project plan",
      "Continuous monitoring: plans",
      "Business impact"
    ],
    "correct": "Business impact"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following would be MOST important to include in an IS audit report?",
    "options": [
      "Specific technology solutions for each audit observation",
      "Observations not reported as findings due to inadequate evidence",
      "The roadmap for addressing the various risk areas",
      "The level of unmitigated risk along with business impact"
    ],
    "correct": "The level of unmitigated risk along with business impact"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the MOST important factor when an organization is developing information security policies and procedures?",
    "options": [
      "Compliance with relevant regulations",
      "Consultation with security staff",
      "Inclusion of mission and objectives",
      "Alignment with an information security framework"
    ],
    "correct": "Alignment with an information security framework"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following should be the GREATEST concern to an IS auditor reviewing the information security framework of an organization.",
    "options": [
      "A list of critical information assets was not included in the information security policy",
      "Senior management was not involved in the development of the information security policy",
      "The information security policy is not aligned with regulatory requirements",
      "The information security policy has not been updated in the last two years"
    ],
    "correct": "The information security policy is not aligned with regulatory requirements"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following would be MOST time and cost efficient when performing a control self-assessment (CSA) for an organization with a large number of widely dispersed employees?",
    "options": [
      "Survey questionnaire",
      "Engaging external consultants",
      "Top-down and bottom-up analysis",
      "Face-to-face interviews"
    ],
    "correct": "Survey questionnaire"
  },
  {
    "question": "An audit identified weak password controls in a database system Which of the following provides the BEST evidence that the audit finding has been remediated?",
    "options": [
      "Attestation from database administrators (DBAs) that password settings have been updated",
      "Review of database administrator (DBA) procedures",
      "Observation of updated password settings with database administrators (DBAs)",
      "Interviews with management about remediation completion"
    ],
    "correct": "Observation of updated password settings with database administrators (DBAs)"
  },
  {
    "question": "To ensure adequate security and controls in e-commerce applications which of the following manages the certificate life cycle of public key pairs?",
    "options": [
      "Registration authority (RA)",
      "Certification practice statement (CPS)",
      "Certification revocation list (CRL)",
      "Certification authority (CA)"
    ],
    "correct": "Certification authority (CA)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the BEST data integrity check?",
    "options": [
      "Tracing data back to the point of origin",
      "Preparing and running test data",
      "Performing a sequence check",
      "Counting the transactions processed per day"
    ],
    "correct": "Tracing data back to the point of origin"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following BEST indicates that an incident management process is effective?",
    "options": [
      "Increased number of reported critical incidents",
      "Increased number of incidents reviewed by IT management",
      "Decreased time for incident resolution",
      "Decreased number of calls to the help desk"
    ],
    "correct": "Decreased time for incident resolution"
  },
  {
    "question": "An IS auditor can BEST evaluate the business impact of system failures by",
    "options": [
      "Interviewing the security administrator",
      "Analyzing equipment maintenance logs",
      "Reviewing system-generated logs",
      "Assessing user satisfaction levels."
    ],
    "correct": "Assessing user satisfaction levels."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following provides the BEST evidence that all elements of a business continuity plan (BCP) are operating effectively?",
    "options": [
      "Tabletop test results",
      "Simulation test results",
      "Full operational test results ",
      "Walk-through test results"
    ],
    "correct": "Full operational test results"
  },
  {
    "question": "When an IS audit reveals that a firewall was unable to recognize a number of attack attempts the auditor's BEST recommendation is to place an intrusion detection system (IDS) between the firewall and:",
    "options": [
      "The organization's network",
      "The Internet",
      "The demilitarized zone (DMZ)",
      "The organization's web server"
    ],
    "correct": "The Internet"
  },
  {
    "question": "An organization has decided to purchase a web-based email service from a third-party vendor and eliminate its own email server infrastructure. What type of cloud computing environment would BEST meet the organization s objective?",
    "options": [
      "Software as a Service (SaaS)",
      "Database as a Service (DBaaS)",
      "Platform as a Service (PaaS)",
      "Infrastructure as a Service (laaS)"
    ],
    "correct": "Software as a Service (SaaS)"
  },
  {
    "question": "A white box testing method is applicable with which of the following testing processes?",
    "options": [
      "Sociability testing",
      "Parallel testing",
      "Integration testing",
      "User acceptance testing (UAT)"
    ],
    "correct": "Integration testing"
  },
  {
    "question": "IT disaster recovery time objectives (RTOs) should be based on the",
    "options": [
      "maximum tolerable downtime (MTD)",
      "system interdependencies",
      "maximum tolerable loss of data",
      "mean time to restore (MTTR)"
    ],
    "correct": "system interdependencies"
  },
  {
    "question": " An organization is shifting to a remote workforce, in preparation, the IT department is performing stress and capacity testing of remote access infrastructure and systems. What type of control is being implemented?",
    "options": [
      "Compensating",
      "Detective",
      "Directive",
      "Preventive"
    ],
    "correct": "Preventive"
  },
  {
    "question": "The PRIMARY benefit of automating application testing is to",
    "options": [
      "provide more flexibility",
      "reduce the time to review code",
      "provide test consistency",
      "replace all manual test processes"
    ],
    "correct": "provide test consistency"
  },
  {
    "question": "When reviewing past results of a recurring annual audit, an IS auditor notes that findings may not have been reported and independence may not have been maintained Which of the following is the auditor's BEST course of action?",
    "options": [
      "Inform audit management",
      "Reevaluate internal controls.",
      "Re-perform past audits to ensure independence",
      "Inform senior management"
    ],
    "correct": "Inform audit management"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following components of a service level agreement (SLA) provides the GREATEST assurance that service provider production issues will be resolved promptly.",
    "options": [
      "Right to audit the service provider upon request",
      "Penalties for noncompliance",
      "Documented processes for dispute resolution",
      "Indemnity clause against liabilities"
    ],
    "correct": "Documented processes for dispute resolution"
  },
  {
    "question": " When developing customer-facing IT applications, in which stage of the system development life cycle (SDLC) is it MOST beneficial to consider data privacy principles",
    "options": [
      "Requirements definition",
      "Systems design and architecture",
      "Software selection and acquisition",
      "User acceptance testing (UAT)"
    ],
    "correct": "Requirements definition"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the GREATEST risk related to the use of virtualized environments?",
    "options": [
      "There may be increased potential for session hijacking",
      "Ability to change operating systems may be limited",
      "The host may be a potential single point of failure within the system",
      "There may be insufficient processing capacity to assign to guests"
    ],
    "correct": "The host may be a potential single point of failure within the system"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following should an organization do to anticipate the effects of a disaster?",
    "options": [
      "Develop a business impact analysis (BIA)",
      "Simulate a disaster recovery",
      "Define recovery point objectives (RPOs)",
      "Analyze capability maturity model gaps"
    ],
    "correct": "Develop a business impact analysis (BIA)"
  },
  {
    "question": "An IT governance body wants to determine whether IT service delivery is based on consistently effective processes. Which of the following is the BEST approach?",
    "options": [
      "Develop a maturity model",
      "Conduct a gap analysis",
      "Evaluate key performance indicators (KPIs)",
      "Implement a control self-assessment (CSA)"
    ],
    "correct": "Evaluate key performance indicators (KPIs)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following provides the BEST evidence that outsourced provider services are being properly managed?",
    "options": [
      "Adequate action is taken for noncompliance with the service level agreement (SLA)",
      "The service level agreement (SLA) includes penalties for non-performance",
      "The vendor provides historical data to demonstrate its performance",
      "Internal performance standards align with corporate strategy"
    ],
    "correct": "The vendor provides historical data to demonstrate its performance"
  },
  {
    "question": "During an audit, the IS auditor finds that in many cases excessive rights were not removed from a system Which of the following is the auditor's BEST recommendation?",
    "options": [
      "IT security should regularly revoke excessive system rights",
      "Human resources (HR) should delete access rights of terminated employees",
      "Line management should regularly review and request modification of access rights",
      "System administrators should ensure consistency of assigned rights"
    ],
    "correct": "Line management should regularly review and request modification of access rights"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following should be the PRIMARY objective of conducting an audit follow-up of management action plans?",
    "options": [
      "To identify new risks and controls for the organization",
      "To ensure senior management is aware of the audit findings",
      "To verify that risks listed in the audit report have been properly mitigated",
      "To align the management action plans with business requirements"
       ],
    "correct": "To verify that risks listed in the audit report have been properly mitigated"
  },
  {
      "question": "An IS auditor is reviewing the contract for a customer relationship management (CRM) system containing personal identifiable information (Pll) hosted by a third party The absence of which of the following would be the GREATEST concern regarding the contract?",
    "options": [
      "Right-to-audit clause",
      "System availability requirements",
      "Confidentiality terms",
      "Service level agreements (SLAs)"
    ],
    "correct": "Confidentiality terms"
  },
  {
    "question": "During an audit of a data center with updated technology, the auditee indicates that environmental controls are the same as those used in the previous environment The IS auditor should FIRST",
    "options": [
      "Review equipment specifications",
      "Recommend changes to the maintenance schedule",
      "Determine whether the controls are active",
      "Test selected controls."
    ],
    "correct": "Test selected controls."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following BEST describes the role of the IS auditor in a control self-assessment (CSA)",
    "options": [
      "Implementer",
      "Approver",
      "Facilitator",
      "Reviewer"
    ],
    "correct": "Facilitator"
  },
  {
    "question": "During which process is regression testing MOST commonly used?",
    "options": [
      "Unit testing",
      "System modification",
      "Stress testing",
      "Program development"
    ],
    "correct": "System modification"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following BEST reflects a mature strategic planning process?",
    "options": [
      "IT projects from the strategic plan are approved by management",
      "Action plans with IT requirements built into all projects",
      "An IT strategic plan with specifications of controls and safeguards",
      "An IT strategic plan that supports the corporate strategy"
    ],
    "correct": "An IT strategic plan that supports the corporate strategy"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following statements appearing in an organization's acceptable use policy BEST demonstrates alignment with data classification standards related to the protection of information assets?",
    "options": [
      "Any Information assets transmitted over a public network must be approved by executive management.",
      "All information assets will be assigned a clearly defined level to facilitate proper employee handling.",
      "Information assets should only be accessed by persons with a justified need.",
      "All information assets must be encrypted when stored on the organization's systems"
    ],
    "correct": "All information assets will be assigned a clearly defined level to facilitate proper employee handling."
  },
  {
    "question": " Of the following, who is accountable for ensuring the representation of major stakeholders involved in a project?",
    "options": [
      "Change control board",
      "Steering committee",
      "Project manager",
      "Project management office (PMO)"
    ],
    "correct": "Steering committee"
  },
  {
    "question": "The MOST important measure of the effectiveness of an organization\u0092s security program is the",
    "options": [
      "number of new vulnerabilities reported",
      "comparison with critical incidents experienced by competitors",
      "adverse impact of incidents on critical business activities",
      "number of vulnerability alerts escalated to senior management"
    ],
    "correct": "adverse impact of incidents on critical business activities"
  },
  {
    "question": "Audit frameworks can assist the IS audit function by",
    "options": [
      "outlining the specific steps needed to complete audits",
      "defining the authority and responsibility of the IS audit function",
      "providing details on how to execute the audit program",
      "providing direction and information regarding the performance of audits"
    ],
    "correct": "providing direction and information regarding the performance of audits"
  },
  {
    "question": "An organization outsources its payroll function to a third-party service provider Which of the following is MOST important for an IS auditor to verify when reviewing the outsourcing agreement?",
    "options": [
      "The provider has a good service reputation",
      "The provider aligns with payroll industry best practices",
      "The provider has an extensive security training program",
      "The provider has agreed to a right-to-audit clause"
    ],
    "correct": "The provider has agreed to a right-to-audit clause"
  },
  {
    "question": "An IS auditor has been asked to advise on measures to improve IT governance within the organization Which of the following is the BEST recommendation?",
    "options": [
      "Benchmark organizational performance against industry peers",
      "Implement key performance indicators (KPIs)",
      "Require executive management to draft IT strategy",
      "Implement annual third-party audits"
    ],
    "correct": "Implement key performance indicators (KPIs)"
  },
  {
    "question": "A computer forensic audit is MOST relevant in which of the following situations:",
    "options": [
      "Missing server patches",
      "Data loss due to hacking of servers",
      "Mismatches in transaction data",
      "Inadequate controls in the IT environment"
    ],
    "correct": "Data loss due to hacking of servers"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the BEST way to prevent social engineering incidents?",
    "options": [
      "Include security responsibilities in job descriptions and require signed acknowledgment,",
      "Ensure user workstations are running the most recent version of antivirus software.",
      "Enforce strict email security gateway controls",
      "Maintain an onboarding and annual security awareness program"
    ],
    "correct": "Maintain an onboarding and annual security awareness program"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following should an IS auditor be MOST concerned with during a post-implementation review?",
    "options": [
      "The system contains several minor defects",
      "The system was over budget by 15%",
      "The system does not have a maintenance plan",
      "The system deployment was delayed by three weeks"
    ],
    "correct": "The system does not have a maintenance plan"
  },
  {
    "question": "An IS auditor finds that a recently deployed application has a number of developers with inappropriate update access left over from the testing environment Which of the following would have BEST prevented the update access from being migrated?",
    "options": [
      "Holding the application owner accountable for application security",
      "Including a step within the system development life cycle (SDLC) to clean up access prior to go-live",
      "Establishing a role-based matrix for provisioning users",
      "Re-assigning user access rights in the quality assurance (QA) environment"
    ],
    "correct": "Including a step within the system development life cycle (SDLC) to clean up access prior to go-live"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the BEST control to help detect input errors in the customer account number field during accounts receivable transaction processing?",
    "options": [
      "Parity check",
      "Checksum",
      "Validity check",
      "Limit check"
    ],
    "correct": "Validity check"
  },
  {
    "question": "A post-implementation review was conducted by issuing a survey to users Which of the following should be of GREATEST concern to an IS auditor?",
    "options": [
      "The survey results were not presented in detail to management",
      "The survey questions did not address the scope of the business case",
      "The survey was issued to employees a month after implementation",
      "The survey form template did not allow additional feedback to be provided"
    ],
    "correct": "The survey questions did not address the scope of the business case"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following approaches would utilize data analytics to facilitate the testing of a new account creation process?",
    "options": [
      "Review new account applications submitted in the past month for invalid dates of birth.",
      "Review the business requirements document for date of birth field requirements",
      "Attempt to submit new account applications with invalid dates of birth",
      "Evaluate configuration settings for the date of birth field requirements"
    ],
    "correct": "Review new account applications submitted in the past month for invalid dates of birth."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is MOST important for an IS auditor to verify when reviewing an organization's data classification policy?",
    "options": [
      "The policy requires the implementation of data loss prevention (DLP) tools",
      "The policy defines a classification scheme for different levels of sensitivity",
      "The policy provides for a uniform level of protection for the organization's data",
      "The policy aligns with industry best practice for data classification"
    ],
    "correct": "The policy defines a classification scheme for different levels of sensitivity"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following BEST enables an IS auditor to prioritize financial reporting spreadsheets for an end-user computing (EUC) audit*?",
    "options": [
      "Ascertaining which spreadsheets are most frequently used",
      "Understanding the purpose of each spreadsheet",
      "Identifying the spreadsheets with built-in macros",
      "Reviewing spreadsheets based on file size"
    ],
    "correct": "Understanding the purpose of each spreadsheet"
  },
  {
    "question": "__ is the PRIMARY reason to adopt a risk-based IS audit strategy?",
    "options": [
      "To identify key threats risks",
      "and controls for the organization",
      "To prioritize available resources and focus on areas with significant risk",
      "To achieve synergy between audit and other risk management functions",
      "To reduce the time and effort needed to perform a full audit cycle"
    ],
    "correct": "To prioritize available resources and focus on areas with significant risk"
  },
  {
    "question": " When building or upgrading enterprise cryptographic infrastructure, which of the following is the MOST critical requirement for growing business environments?",
    "options": [
      "Scalable architectures and systems",
      "Network throttling",
      "Service discovery",
      "Backup and restoration capabilities"
    ],
    "correct": "Scalable architectures and systems"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which of the following sampling methodologies does each population subgroup have a probability of being selected?",
    "options": [
      "Random sampling",
      "Statistical sampling",
      "Quota sampling",
      "Stratified sampling"
    ],
    "correct": "Stratified sampling"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following should be the MOST important consideration when conducting a review of IT portfolio management*?",
    "options": [
      "Assignment of responsibility for each project to an IT team member",
      "Adherence to best practice and industry approved methodologies",
      "Controls to minimize risk and maximize value for the IT portfolio",
      "Frequency of meetings where the business discusses the IT portfolio"
    ],
    "correct": "Controls to minimize risk and maximize value for the IT portfolio"
  },
  {
    "question": "An IS audit review identifies inconsistencies in privacy requirements across third-party service provider contracts Which of the following is the BEST recommendation to address this situation?",
    "options": [
      "Suspend contracts with third-party providers that handle sensitive data",
      "Require third-party providers to sign nondisclosure agreements (NDAs)",
      "Review privacy requirements when contracts come up for renewal",
      "Prioritize contract amendments for third-party providers"
    ],
    "correct": "Prioritize contract amendments for third-party providers"
  },
  {
    "question": "The PRIMARY purpose of a configuration management system is to:",
    "options": [
      "define baselines for software",
      "track software updates",
      "support the release procedure",
      "standardize change approval"
    ],
    "correct": "define baselines for software"
  },
  {
    "question": " Following the sale of a business division, employees will be transferred to a new organization, but they will retain access to IT equipment from the previous employer An IS auditor has recommended that both organizations agree to and document an acceptable use policy for the equipment. What type of control has been recommended?",
    "options": [
      "Detective control",
      "Preventive control",
      "Directive control",
      "Corrective control"
    ],
    "correct": "Directive control"
  },
  {
    "question": "A project team has decided to switch to an agile approach to develop a replacement for an existing business application Which of the following should an IS auditor do FIRST to ensure the effectiveness of the project audit?",
    "options": [
      "Interview business process owners to compile a list of business requirements",
      "Compare the agile process with previous methodology.",
      "Understand the specific agile methodology that will be followed",
      "Identity and assess existing agile process controls"
    ],
    "correct": "Understand the specific agile methodology that will be followed"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the PRIMARY benefit of using a SIEM tool to collate high amounts of data collected across various security tools?",
    "options": [
      "Reducing the number of isolated events noted as incidents",
      "Decreasing the effort needed to monitor security events",
      "Correlating many isolated events to create a single source of record",
      "Reducing the number of false positive incidents"
    ],
    "correct": "Correlating many isolated events to create a single source of record"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following should be an IS auditor's GREATEST concern when reviewing an organization's security controls for policy compliance?",
    "options": [
      "Security policies are not applicable across all business units",
      "Security policy documents are available on a public domain website",
      "The security policy has not been reviewed within the past year",
      "End users are not required to acknowledge security policy training"
    ],
    "correct": "Security policies are not applicable across all business units"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the GREATEST risk of using a reciprocal site for disaster recovery?",
    "options": [
      "Equipment compatibility issues at the site",
      "Inability to test the recovery plans onsite",
      "Inability to utilize the site when required",
      "Mismatched organizational security policies"
    ],
    "correct": "Inability to utilize the site when required"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the MAIN risk associated with adding a new system functionality during the development phase without following a project change management process'?",
    "options": [
      "The project may go over budget",
      "The added functionality has not been documented",
      "The new functionality may not meet requirements",
      "The project may fail to meet the established deadline"
    ],
    "correct": "The new functionality may not meet requirements"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is MOST likely to be reduced when implementing optimal risk management strategies?",
    "options": [
      "Detection risk",
      "Sampling risk",
      "Residual risk",
      "Inherent risk"
    ],
    "correct": "Residual risk"
  },
  {
    "question": " Following a breach, what is the BEST source to determine the maximum amount of time before customers must be notified that their personal information may have been compromised'?",
    "options": [
      "Industry standards",
      "Information security policy",
      "Incident response plan",
      "Industry regulations"
    ],
    "correct": "Industry regulations"
  },
  {
    "question": " During audit planning, when is it MOST appropriate for an IS auditor to rely on a third-party provider s external audit report on service-level management?",
    "options": [
      "When the report confirms that service levels were not violated",
      "When the scope and methodology meet audit requirements",
      "When the provider is independently certified and accredited",
      "When the report was released within the last 12 months"
    ],
    "correct": "When the scope and methodology meet audit requirements"
  },
  {
    "question": " In an area susceptible to unexpected Increases in electrical power, which of the following would MOST effectively protect the system?",
    "options": [
      "Circuit breaker",
      "Alternate power supply line",
      "Generator",
      "Voltage regulator"
    ],
    "correct": "Voltage regulator"
  },
  {
    "question": "An IS auditor is verifying the adequacy of an organization's internal controls and is concerned about potential circumvention of regulations Which of the following is the BEST sampling method to use?",
    "options": [
      "Random sampling",
      "Variable sampling",
      "Cluster sampling",
      "Attribute sampling"
    ],
    "correct": "Attribute sampling"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following would BEST indicate the effectiveness of a security awareness training program",
    "options": [
      "Employee satisfaction with training",
      "Reduced unintentional violations",
      "Results of third-party social engineering tests",
      "Increased number of employees completing training"
    ],
    "correct": "Results of third-party social engineering tests"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the MOST important issue for an IS auditor to consider with regard to Voice-over IP (VoIP) communications?",
    "options": [
      "Nonrepudiation",
      "Homogeneity of the network",
      "Identity management",
      "Continuity of service"
    ],
    "correct": "Homogeneity of the network"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is MOST important for an IS auditor to evaluate when auditing proposed investments for the acquisition of an enterprise-wide application?",
    "options": [
      "Whether management has approved a business case for the application",
      "Whether there are multiple business units interested in the application",
      "Whether business units have approved user acceptance testing (UAT) for the application",
      "Whether there are independent case studies regarding use of the application"
    ],
    "correct": "Whether management has approved a business case for the application"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following presents the GREATEST risk associated with end-user computing (EUC) applications over financial reporting?",
    "options": [
      "Inability to quickly modify and deploy a solution",
      "Lack of portability for users",
      "Loss of time due to manual processes",
      "Calculation errors in spreadsheets"
    ],
    "correct": "Calculation errors in spreadsheets"
  },
  {
    "question": "An IS auditor is performing a follow-up audit and notes that some critical deficiencies have not been addressed the auditor s BEST course of action is to",
    "options": [
      "assess the impact of not addressing deficiencies.",
      "document management s reasons for not addressing deficiencies",
      "provide new recommendations",
      "postpone the audit until the deficiencies are addressed"
    ],
    "correct": "assess the impact of not addressing deficiencies."
  },
  {
    "question": " An organization has established three IT processing environments: development, test, and production The MAJOR reason for separating the development and test environments is to",
    "options": [
      "perform testing in a stable environment",
      "limit the users access rights to the development environment",
      "protect the programs under development from unauthorized testing",
      "obtain segregation of duties between IT staff and end users"
    ],
    "correct": "perform testing in a stable environment"
  },
  {
    "question": "The record-locking option of a database management system (DBMS) serves to",
    "options": [
      "allow database administrators (DBAs) to record the activities of users",
      "allow users to lock others out of their files",
      "restrict users from changing certain values within records",
      "eliminate the risk of concurrent updates to a record"
    ],
    "correct": "eliminate the risk of concurrent updates to a record"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following should be of GREATEST concern to an IS auditor when using data analytics?",
    "options": [
      "The data set contains Irrelevant fields",
      "The data was not extracted by the auditor",
      "The data analytics software is open source",
      "The data source lacks integrity"
    ],
    "correct": "The data source lacks integrity"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is MOST important when creating a forensic Image of a hard drive?",
    "options": [
      "Choosing an industry-leading forensics software tool",
      "Securing a backup copy of the hard drive",
      "Generating a content hash of the hard drive",
      "Requiring an independent third party be present while imaging"
    ],
    "correct": "Generating a content hash of the hard drive"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is a threat to IS auditor independence?",
    "options": [
      "Internal auditors recommend appropriate controls for systems in development",
      "Internal auditors share the audit plan and control test plans with management prior to audit commencement",
      "Internal auditors attend IT steering committee meetings",
      "Internal auditors design remediation plans to address control gaps identified by internal audit"
    ],
    "correct": "Internal auditors design remediation plans to address control gaps identified by internal audit"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following would be of GREATEST concern to an IS auditor when a multi-function printer device is sent offsite for maintenance'?",
    "options": [
      "The printout has to be redirected to another department",
      "Internal memory does not automatically clear",
      "Maintenance costs exceed the value of the device",
      "Business impact during the maintenance period"
    ],
    "correct": "Internal memory does not automatically clear"
  },
  {
    "question": " An IS audit manager was temporarily tasked with supervising a project manager assigned to the organization's payroll application upgrade Upon returning to the audit department, the audit manager has been asked to perform an audit to validate the implementation of the payroll application The audit manager is the only one in the audit department with IT project management experience What is the BEST course of action?",
    "options": [
      "Transfer the assignment to a different audit manager despite lack of IT project management experience",
      "Have a senior IS auditor manage the project with the IS audit manager performing final review",
      "Manage the audit since there is no one else with the appropriate experience",
      "Outsource the audit to independent and qualified resources"
    ],
    "correct": "Outsource the audit to independent and qualified resources"
  },
  {
    "question": "An organization is permanently transitioning from onsite to fully remote business operations When should the existing business impact analysis (BIA) be reviewed?",
    "options": [
      "As soon as the new operating model is in place",
      "During the next scheduled review",
      "At least one year after the transition",
      "As soon as the decision about the transition is announced"
    ],
    "correct": "As soon as the new operating model is in place"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is PRIMARILY responsible for the design of IT controls to meet control objectives?",
    "options": [
      "Internal auditor",
      "IT manager",
      "Risk management",
      "Business management"
    ],
    "correct": "IT manager"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following conditions should be of GREATEST concern to an IS auditor reviewing change management?",
    "options": [
      "The change management process does not include vendor-supplied changes",
      "Vendors do not have access to apply changes to the quality assurance (QA) environment",
      "The individual applying the changes is not responsible for approving the changes",
      "Change management documentation is not submitted prior to development"
    ],
    "correct": "Change management documentation is not submitted prior to development"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following would MOST effectively help to reduce the number of repeated incidents in an organization?",
    "options": [
      "Testing incident response plans with a wide range of scenarios",
      "Prioritizing incidents after impact assessment",
      "Training incident management teams on current incident trends",
      "Linking incidents to problem management activities"
    ],
    "correct": "Linking incidents to problem management activities"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is MOST important to define within a disaster recovery plan (DRP)?",
    "options": [
      "A comprehensive list of disaster recovery scenarios and priorities",
      "Test results for backup data restoration",
      "Roles and responsibilities for recovery team members",
      "Business continuity plan (BCP)"
    ],
    "correct": "Roles and responsibilities for recovery team members"
  },
  {
    "question": "An IS auditor is performing a compliance review of a bank's clean desk policy While onsite at one of the branches the auditor discovers that the key to a desk that contains customer loan applications is easily accessible Which of the following is the auditor s BEST course of action?",
    "options": [
      "Do not report as the desk is out of scope.",
      "Report the control gap",
      "Recommend shredding the old loan applications",
      "Recommend changing the locks"
    ],
    "correct": "Report the control gap"
  },
  {
    "question": "Due to staff limitations the same individual is responsible for both developing application changes and migrating those changes to production Which of the following should the IS auditor recommend as the BEST compensating control?",
    "options": [
      "Perform quality assurance (QA) testing",
      "Implement secure coding training",
      "Review audit logs",
      "Implement independent code review"
    ],
    "correct": "Implement independent code review"
  },
  {
    "question": "An organization s IT risk assessment should include the identification of:",
    "options": [
      "compensating controls",
      "business process owners",
      "business needs",
      "vulnerabilities"
    ],
    "correct": "business needs"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following technologies has the SMALLEST maximum range for data transmission between devices?",
    "options": [
      "Near-field communication (NFC)",
      "Bluetooth",
      "Wi-Fi",
      "Long-term evolution (LTE)"
    ],
    "correct": "Near-field communication (NFC)"
  },
  {
    "question": "An IS auditor is reviewing a data conversion project Which of the following is the auditor's BEST recommendation prior to go-live?",
    "options": [
      "Establish a configuration baseline",
      "Review test procedures and scenarios",
      "Conduct a mock conversion test",
      "Automate the test scripts"
    ],
    "correct": "Conduct a mock conversion test"
  },
  {
    "question": "What should be the PRIMARY basis for management's decision on whether to make an investment in emerging technologies?",
    "options": [
      "The related business case",
      "Business intelligence tools",
      "The business climate",
      "Industry benchmarks"
    ],
    "correct": "The related business case"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following should be of GREATEST concern to an IS auditor reviewing an organization s business continuity plan (BCP)?",
    "options": [
      "The BCP has not been approved by senior management",
      "The BCP has not been tested since it was first issued",
      "The BCP is not version-controlled",
      "The BCP's contact information needs to be updated"
    ],
    "correct": "The BCP has not been tested since it was first issued"
  },
  {
    "question": "Following a merger a review of an international organization determines the IT steering committee s decisions do not extend to regional offices as required in the consolidated IT operating model Which of the following is the IS auditor's BEST recommendation?",
    "options": [
      "Create regional IT steering committees",
      "Update the IT steering committee\\x92s formal charter",
      "Create regional centers of excellence",
      "Engage an IT governance consultant"
    ],
    "correct": "Update the IT steering committee\u0092s formal charter"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is a characteristic of a digital signature used for securing email transmissions?",
    "options": [
      "The receiver only needs the public key to decrypt the message and verify the signature",
      "The signature is authentic whether or not It has been encrypted",
      "The signature on one message can be transferred to another message",
      "The signed message provides confidentiality and availability protection"
    ],
    "correct": "The receiver only needs the public key to decrypt the message and verify the signature"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following types of firewalls provides the GREATEST degree of control against hacker intrusion?",
    "options": [
      "Circuit gateway",
      "Packet filtering router",
      "Application-level gateway",
      "Screening router"
    ],
    "correct": "Application-level gateway"
  },
  {
    "question": " During a review of an organization\u0092s technology policies, which of the following observations should be of MOST concern to the IS auditor?",
    "options": [
      "A globally acknowledged framework is not used",
      "Business objectives are not defined",
      "Legal requirements are not considered",
      "The policies have not been reviewed within the last three years."
    ],
    "correct": "Business objectives are not defined"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the MAIN reason to use incremental backups?",
    "options": [
      "To minimize the backup time and resources",
      "To increase backup resiliency and redundancy",
      "To improve key availability metrics",
      "To reduce costs associated with backups"
    ],
    "correct": "To minimize the backup time and resources"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following Is MOST important for an IS auditor to look for in a project feasibility study?",
    "options": [
      "An assessment of whether requirements will be fully met",
      "An assessment of whether the expected benefits can be achieved",
      "An assessment indicating security controls will operate effectively",
      "An assessment indicating the benefits will exceed the investment"
    ],
    "correct": "An assessment of whether the expected benefits can be achieved"
  },
  {
    "question": "An IS auditor observes that a business-critical application does not currently have any level of fault tolerance Which of the following is the GREATEST concern with this situation?",
    "options": [
      "Decreased mean time between failures (MTBF)",
      "Limited tolerance for damage",
      "Degradation of services",
      "Single point of failure"
    ],
    "correct": "Single point of failure"
  },
  {
    "question": "What would be the BEST way to incorporate a new data classification program into daily operations?",
    "options": [
      "Ensure the data classification policy is updated on a regular basis",
      "Require and enforce encryption of confidential information",
      "Ensure the organizational focus is on data classified as high priority",
      "Make data classification part of employee security awareness training"
    ],
    "correct": "Make data classification part of employee security awareness training"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which cloud deployment model is MOST likely to be customizable?",
    "options": [
      "Community",
      "Public",
      "Private",
      "Hybrid"
    ],
    "correct": "Private"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following should be the FIRST step in a data migration project?",
    "options": [
      "Understanding the new system's data structure",
      "Completing data cleanup in the current database to eliminate inconsistencies",
      "Reviewing decisions on how business processes should be conducted in the new system",
      "Creating data conversion scripts"
    ],
    "correct": "Completing data cleanup in the current database to eliminate inconsistencies"
  },
  {
    "question": "An IS auditor is preparing a plan for audits to be carried out over a specified period Which of the following activities should the IS auditor perform FIRST?",
    "options": [
      "Allocate audit resources",
      "Prioritize risks",
      "Review prior audit reports",
      "Determine the audit universe"
    ],
    "correct": "Determine the audit universe"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the BEST way to mitigate the impact of ransomware attacks?",
    "options": [
      "Backing up data frequently",
      "Invoking the disaster recovery plan (DRP)",
      "Paying the ransom",
      "Requiring password changes for administrative accounts"
    ],
    "correct": "Backing up data frequently"
  },
  {
    "question": "Management receives information indicating a high level of risk associated with potential flooding near the organization's data center within the next few years As a result, a decision has been made to move data center operations to another facility on higher ground Which approach has been adopted?",
    "options": [
      "Risk reduction",
      "Risk acceptance",
      "Risk avoidance",
      "Risk transfer"
    ],
    "correct": "Risk avoidance"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following indicates that an internal audit organization is structured to support the independence and clarity of the reporting process'?",
    "options": [
      "Auditors are responsible for assessing and operating a system of internal controls",
      "The internal audit manager has a reporting line to the audit committee",
      "Auditors are responsible for performing operational duties or activities",
      "The internal audit manager reports functionally to a senior management official"
    ],
    "correct": "The internal audit manager has a reporting line to the audit committee"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following threats is mitigated by a firewall'?",
    "options": [
      "Intrusion attack",
      "Trojan horse",
      "Passive assault",
      "Asynchronous attack"
    ],
    "correct": "Intrusion attack"
  },
  {
    "question": "During a project assessment an IS auditor finds that business owners have been removed from the project initiation phase Which of the following should be the auditor's GREATEST concern with this situation\"?",
    "options": [
      "Unrealistic milestones",
      "Unclear benefits",
      "Incomplete requirements",
      "Inadequate deliverables"
    ],
    "correct": "Incomplete requirements"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is MOST important for an IS auditor to do during an exit meeting with an auditee?",
    "options": [
      "Request input in determining corrective action",
      "Communicate the recommendations to senior management",
      "Ensure that the facts presented in the report are correct",
      "Specify implementation dates for the recommendations"
    ],
    "correct": "Ensure that the facts presented in the report are correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "An IS auditor is conducting a physical security audit of a healthcare facility and finds closed-circuit television (CCTV) systems located in a patient care area Which of the following is the GREATEST concern\u0094?",
    "options": [
      "The retention period for video recordings is undefined",
      "There are no notices indicating recording is in progress",
      "There are no backups of the videos",
      "Cameras are not monitored 24/7."
    ],
    "correct": "There are no notices indicating recording is in progress"
  },
  {
    "question": "During a project audit an IS auditor notes that project reporting does not accurately reflect current progress Which of the following is the GREATEST resulting impact?",
    "options": [
      "The project reporting to the board of directors will be incomplete",
      "The project will not withstand a quality assurance (QA) review",
      "The project manager will have to be replaced",
      "The project steering committee cannot provide effective governance"
    ],
    "correct": "The project steering committee cannot provide effective governance"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following should an IS auditor ensure is classified at the HIGHEST level of sensitivity?",
    "options": [
      "IT security incidents",
      "Emergency change records",
      "Penetration test results",
      "Server room access history"
    ],
    "correct": "Penetration test results"
  },
  {
    "question": "During a follow-up audit an IS auditor finds that some critical recommendations have not been addressed, as management has decided to accept the risk Which of the following is the IS auditor's BEST course of action?",
    "options": [
      "Evaluate senior management s acceptance of the risk",
      "Adjust the annual risk assessment accordingly",
      "Require the auditee to address the recommendations in full",
      "Update the audit program based on management s acceptance of risk"
    ],
    "correct": "Evaluate senior management s acceptance of the risk"
  },
  {
    "question": "A data centers physical access log system captures each visitor's identification document numbers along with the visitor's photo Which of the following sampling methods would be MOST useful to an IS auditor conducting compliance testing for the effectiveness of the system?",
    "options": [
      "Haphazard sampling",
      "Variable sampling",
      "Attribute sampling",
      "Quota sampling"
    ],
    "correct": "Attribute sampling"
  },
  {
    "question": "During the planning phase of a data loss prevention (DLP) audit management expresses a concern about mobile computing Which of the following should the IS auditor identify as the associated risk?",
    "options": [
      "The use of the cloud negatively impacting IT availability",
      "Lack of governance and oversight for IT infrastructure and applications",
      "Increased need for user awareness training",
      "Increased vulnerability due to anytime anywhere accessibility"
    ],
    "correct": "Increased vulnerability due to anytime anywhere accessibility"
  },
  {
    "question": "A web application is developed in-house by an organization Which of the following would provide the BEST evidence to an IS auditor that the application is secure from external attack?",
    "options": [
      "Code review by a third party",
      "Database application monitoring logs",
      "Penetration test results",
      "Web application firewall (WAF) implementation"
    ],
    "correct": "Penetration test results"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following areas of responsibility would cause the GREATEST segregation of duties conflict if the individual who performs the related tasks also has approval authority?",
    "options": [
      "Invoices and reconciliations",
      "Vendor selection and statements of work (SOWs)",
      "Goods receipts and payments",
      "Purchase requisitions and purchase orders"
    ],
    "correct": "Goods receipts and payments"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following should be the PRIMARY basis for prioritizing follow-up audits?",
    "options": [
      "Recommendation from executive management",
      "Audit cycle defined in the audit plan",
      "Residual risk from the findings of previous audits",
      "Complexity of management's action plans"
    ],
    "correct": "Residual risk from the findings of previous audits"
  },
  {
    "question": "A new system development project is running late against a critical implementation deadline Which of the following is the MOST important activity?",
    "options": [
      "Perform a pre-implementation audit",
      "Perform user acceptance testing (UAT)",
      "Document last-minute enhancements",
      "Ensure that code has been reviewed"
    ],
    "correct": "Document last-minute enhancements"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following approaches will ensure recovery time objectives (RTOs) are met for an organization\u0092s disaster recovery plan (DRP)?",
    "options": [
      "Performing a full interruption test",
      "Performing a tabletop test",
      "Performing a cyber resilience test",
      "Performing a parallel test"
    ],
    "correct": "Performing a full interruption test"
  },
  {
    "question": "An IS auditor is reviewing a contract for the outsourcing of IT facilities If missing which of the following should present the GREATEST concern to the auditor\u0092",
    "options": [
      "Help desk availability",
      "Perimeter network security diagram",
      "Access control requirements",
      "Hardware configurations"
    ],
    "correct": "Access control requirements"
  },
  {
    "question": "The IS quality assurance (QA) group is responsible for:",
    "options": [
      "designing procedures to protect data against accidental disclosure",
      "ensuring that program changes adhere to established standards",
      "monitoring the execution of computer processing tasks",
      "ensuring that the output received from system processing is complete"
    ],
    "correct": "ensuring that program changes adhere to established standards"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following applications has the MOST inherent risk and should be prioritized during audit planning\u0092",
    "options": [
      "An internally developed application",
      "A decommissioned legacy application",
      "An onsite application that is unsupported",
      "An outsourced accounting application"
    ],
    "correct": "An onsite application that is unsupported"
  },
  {
    "question": "A checksum is classified as which type of control?",
    "options": [
      "Detective control",
      "Corrective control",
      "Preventive control",
      "Administrative control"
    ],
    "correct": "Detective control"
  },
  {
    "question": "During which IT project phase is it MOST appropriate to conduct a benefits realization analysis?",
    "options": [
      "Post-implementation review phase",
      "Final Implementation phase",
      "Design review phase",
      "User acceptance testing (UAT) phase"
    ],
    "correct": "Post-implementation review phase"
  },
  {
    "question": "An IS auditor is reviewing a bank's service level agreement (SLA) with a third-party provider that hosts the bank's secondary data center. Which of the following findings should be of GREATEST concern to the auditor?",
    "options": [
      "Backup data is hosted online only",
      "The recovery point objective (RPO) has a shorter duration than documented in the disaster recovery plan (DRP)",
      "The recovery time objective (RTO) has a longer duration than documented in the disaster recovery plan (DRP)",
      "The SLA has not been reviewed in more than a year"
    ],
    "correct": "The recovery time objective (RTO) has a longer duration than documented in the disaster recovery plan (DRP)"
  },
  {
    "question": "During a review an IS auditor discovers that corporate users are able to access cloud-based applications and data from any Internet-connected web browser Which of the following is the auditor's BEST recommendation to help prevent unauthorized access?",
    "options": [
      "Update security policies and procedures",
      "Implement multi-factor authentication",
      "Implement an intrusion detection system (IDS).",
      "Utilize strong anti-malware controls on all computing devices."
    ],
    "correct": "Implement multi-factor authentication"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the MOST effective accuracy control for entry of a valid numeric part number?",
    "options": [
      "Online review of description",
      "Hash totals",
      "Self-checking digit",
      "Comparison to historical order pattern"
    ],
    "correct": "Self-checking digit"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following should be the FIRST step when developing a data loss prevention (DLP) solution for a large organization?",
    "options": [
      "Conduct a data inventory and classification exercise",
      "Conduct a threat analysis against sensitive data usage",
      "Create the DLP policies and templates",
      "Identify approved data workflows across the enterprise"
    ],
    "correct": "Conduct a data inventory and classification exercise"
  },
  {
    "question": "When designing metrics for information security, the MOST important consideration is that the metrics:",
    "options": [
      "apply to all business units",
      "are easy to understand.",
      "provide actionable data",
      "conform to industry standards"
    ],
    "correct": "provide actionable data"
  },
  {
    "question": "During a follow-up audit, an IS auditor discovers that a recommendation has not been implemented However, the auditee has implemented a manual workaround that addresses the identified risk less efficiently than the recommended action would Which of the following is the auditor's BEST course of action?",
    "options": [
      "Notify management that the risk has been addressed and take no further action",
      "Require management to implement the original recommendation",
      "Note that the risk has been addressed and notify management of the inefficiency",
      "Escalate the remaining issue for further discussion and resolution"
    ],
    "correct": "Note that the risk has been addressed and notify management of the inefficiency"
  },
  {
    "question": "To help determine whether a controls-reliant approach to auditing financial systems in a company should be used which sequence of IS audit work is MOST appropriate?",
    "options": [
      "Review of the general IS controls followed by a review of the application controls",
      "Detailed examination of financial transactions followed by review of the general ledger",
      "Review of application controls followed by a test of key business process controls",
      "Review of major financial applications followed by a review of IT governance processes"
    ],
    "correct": "Review of the general IS controls followed by a review of the application controls"
  },
  {
    "question": "An IS auditor has identified that as users change departments or leave the company, their access is not adjusted. Which of the following would BEST help to address this situation?",
    "options": [
      "Publish user access management policies",
      "Assign user administration rights to line management",
      "Mandate periodic password changes",
      "Perform periodic access re-certification"
    ],
    "correct": "Perform periodic access re-certification"
  },
  {
    "question": "The process of applying a hash function to a message and obtaining and ciphering a digest refers to",
    "options": [
      "digital certificates,",
      "authentication",
      "public key infrastructure (PKI)",
      "digital signatures"
    ],
    "correct": "digital signatures"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a data center audit, an IS auditor finds that the humidity level is very low The IS auditor would be MOST concerned because of an expected increase in:",
    "options": [
      "risk of fire",
      "employee discomfort",
      "backup tape failures,",
      "static electricity problems."
    ],
    "correct": "static electricity problems."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following should be of GREATEST concern to an IS auditor assessing the effectiveness of an organization's information security governance?",
    "options": [
      "The information security policy does not extend to service providers.",
      "The information security policy is not reviewed by executive management",
      "There is no process to measure information security performance.",
      "Risk assessments of information assets are not periodically performed."
    ],
    "correct": "The information security policy does not extend to service providers."
  },
  {
    "question": "What should be the PRIMARY objective of performing a risk assessment when planning for an IS audit engagement?",
    "options": [
      "To identify high-risk business processes",
      "To reduce risk to an acceptable level",
      "To minimize the number of resources allocated to the engagement",
      "To minimize the level of substantive testing required"
    ],
    "correct": "To identify high-risk business processes"
  },
  {
    "question": "During an information security review an IS auditor learns an organizational policy requires all employees to attend information security training during the first week of each new year What is the auditor's BEST recommendation to ensure employees hired after January receive adequate guidance regarding security awareness\u0092",
    "options": [
      "Ensure new employees read and sign acknowledgment of the acceptable use policy",
      "Revise the policy to require security training every six months for all employees",
      "Require management of new employees to provide an overview of security awareness.",
      "Revise the policy to include security training during onboarding"
    ],
    "correct": "Revise the policy to include security training during onboarding"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the PRIMARY reason an IS auditor would recommend offsite backups although critical data is already on a redundant array of inexpensive disks (RAID)?",
    "options": [
      "Disks of the array cannot be hot-swapped for quick recovery",
      "The array cannot recover from a natural disaster",
      "The array cannot offer protection against disk corruption",
      "The array relies on proper maintenance"
    ],
    "correct": "The array cannot recover from a natural disaster"
  },
  {
    "question": "During a financial accounting audit an IS auditor finds that the IT general controls are deficient Which of the following is the MOST effective course of action to complete the audit?",
    "options": [
      "Place greater reliance on the framework of control",
      "Conduct an IT risk assessment",
      "Place greater reliance on the financial application controls",
      "Increase the substantive testing of the financial balances"
    ],
    "correct": "Place greater reliance on the financial application controls"
  },
  {
    "question": "An organization s business continuity plan (BCP) should be",
    "options": [
      "updated before an independent audit review",
      "tested after an intrusion attempt into the organization s hot site",
      "updated based on changes to personnel and environments",
      "tested whenever new applications are implemented"
    ],
    "correct": "tested whenever new applications are implemented"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following practices associated with capacity planning provides the GREATEST assurance that future incidents related to existing server performance will be prevented?",
    "options": [
      "Performing a root cause analysis for past performance incidents",
      "Duplicating existing disk drive systems to improve redundancy and data storage",
      "Reviewing results from simulated high-demand stress test scenarios",
      "Anticipating current service level agreements (SLAs)will remain unchanged"
    ],
    "correct": "Performing a root cause analysis for past performance incidents"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the BEST way to strengthen the security of smart devices to prevent data leakage?",
    "options": [
      "Enforce strong security settings on smart devices",
      "Include usage restrictions in bring your own device (BYOD) security procedures",
      "Require employees to formally acknowledge security procedures",
      "Review access logs to the organization\\x92s sensitive data in a timely manner"
    ],
    "correct": "Enforce strong security settings on smart devices"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which type of threat can utilize a large group of automated social media accounts to steal data send spam or launch distributed denial of service (DOoS) attacks?",
    "options": [
      "Phishing attempt",
      "Malware sharing",
      "Botnet attack",
      "Data mining"
    ],
    "correct": "Botnet attack"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following tasks would cause the GREATEST segregation of duties (SoD) concern if performed by the person who reconciles the organization's device inventory-?",
    "options": [
      "Creating the device policy",
      "Tracking devices used for spare parts",
      "Approving the issuing of devices",
      "Issuing devices to employees"
    ],
    "correct": "Approving the issuing of devices"
  },
  {
    "question": "During an IS audit of a data center, it was found that programmers are allowed to make emergency fixes to operational programs Which of the following should be the IS auditor s PRIMARY recommendation?",
    "options": [
      "Bypass user ID procedures should be put in place to ensure that the changes are subject to after-the-event approval and testing",
      "The ability to undertake emergency fixes should be restricted to selected key personnel",
      "Emergency program changes should be subject to program migration and testing procedures before they are applied to operational systems",
      "Programmers should be allowed to implement emergency fixes only after obtaining verbal agreement from the application owner"
    ],
    "correct": "Bypass user ID procedures should be put in place to ensure that the changes are subject to after-the-event approval and testing"
  },
  {
    "question": "An IS audit manager is preparing the staffing plan for an audit engagement of a cloud service provider. What should be the manager's PRIMARY concern when being made aware that a new auditor in the department previously worked for this provider?",
    "options": [
      "Independence",
      "Professional conduct",
      "Resource availability",
      "Subject matter expertise"
    ],
    "correct": "Independence"
  },
  {
    "question": "An organization has decided to build a data warehouse using source data from several disparate systems to support strategic decision-making Which of the following is the BEST way to ensure the accuracy and completeness of the data used to support business decisions?",
    "options": [
      "The source data is pre-selected so that it already supports senior management's desired business decision outcome",
      "The source data is from the current year of operations so that irrelevant data from prior years is not included",
      "The source data is modified in the data warehouse to remove confidential or sensitive information",
      "The source data is standardized and cleansed before loading into the data warehouse"
    ],
    "correct": "The source data is standardized and cleansed before loading into the data warehouse"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the MOST effective way to evaluate the physical security of a data center?",
    "options": [
      "Review camera footage from the data center",
      "Perform a data center tour",
      "Interview data center stakeholders",
      "Review data center access logs"
    ],
    "correct": "Perform a data center tour"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following would be of GREATEST concern to an IS auditor reviewing an IT-related customer service project?",
    "options": [
      "The organization will be the first to offer the proposed services",
      "Executing the project will require additional investments.",
      "The project risk exceeds the organization's risk appetite",
      "Expected business value is expressed in qualitative terms"
    ],
    "correct": "The project risk exceeds the organization's risk appetite"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following provides the BEST audit evidence that a firewall is configured in compliance with the organization s security policy?",
    "options": [
      "Analyzing how the configuration changes are performed",
      "Performing penetration testing",
      "Analyzing log files",
      "Reviewing the rule base"
    ],
    "correct": "Reviewing the rule base"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following findings would be of GREATEST concern when auditing an organization's end-user computing (EUC)?",
    "options": [
      "Inconsistency of patching processes being followed",
      "Errors flowed through to financial statements",
      "Reduced oversight by the IT department",
      "Inability to monitor EUC audit logs and activities"
    ],
    "correct": "Errors flowed through to financial statements"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following BEST describes an audit risk\\x92', 'The company is being sued for false accusations.",
    "options": [
      "The financial report may contain undetected material errors",
      "Key employees have not taken vacation for two years",
      "Employees have been misappropriating funds"
    ],
    "correct": "The financial report may contain undetected material errors"
  },
  {
    "question": "An IS auditor finds that the access-controlled doors to a work area are kept unlocked during power outages Which of the following is the auditor's BEST course of action",
    "options": [
      "Recommend keeping the doors locked at all times",
      "Determine whether there are compensating controls",
      "Report the finding to management as high-risk",
      "Confirm whether the practice complies with the security policy"
    ],
    "correct": "Determine whether there are compensating controls"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the BEST indication that there are potential problems within an organization's IT service desk function'?",
    "options": [
      "Lack of segregation of duties",
      "An excessive backlog of user requests",
      "Undocumented operating procedures",
      "Lack of key performance indicators (KPIs)"
    ],
    "correct": "An excessive backlog of user requests"
  },
  {
    "question": "An organization has implemented a new data classification scheme and asks the IS auditor to evaluate its effectiveness Which of the following would be of GREATE ST concern to the auditor1?",
    "options": [
      "The compliance manager decides how the information should be classified",
      "The organization has created a dozen different classification categories",
      "End-user managers determine who should access what information",
      "The organization classifies most of its information as confidential"
    ],
    "correct": "The compliance manager decides how the information should be classified"
  },
  {
    "question": "In order for a firewall to effectively protect a network against external attacks what fundamental practice must be followed?",
    "options": [
      "All external communication must be via the firewall",
      "Filters for external information must be defined",
      "Only essential external services should be permitted",
      "The firewall must be placed in the demiftarized zone (DMZ)"
    ],
    "correct": "All external communication must be via the firewall"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the FIRST step when determining the feasibility of using data analytics in an audit?",
    "options": [
      "Review the data classification schema",
      "Determine if the data can be analyzed",
      "Establish the availability of relevant data",
      "Review the results of prior audits in the same area."
    ],
    "correct": "Establish the availability of relevant data"
  },
  {
    "question": "An IS auditor finds that a number of key patches have not been applied in a timely manner due Io resource constraints Which of the following is the GREATEST risk to the organization in this situation?",
    "options": [
      "Different systems may not be compatible",
      "Known security vulnerabilities may not be mitigated",
      "Systems may not be supported by the vendor",
      "The systems may not meet user requirements"
    ],
    "correct": "Known security vulnerabilities may not be mitigated"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following should be of GREATEST concern for an IS auditor reviewing an organization s disaster recovery plan (DRP)?",
    "options": [
      "The DRP has not been updated since an IT infrastructure upgrade",
      "The DRP has not been formally approved by senior management",
      "The DRP has not been distributed to end users",
      "The DRP contains recovery procedures for critical servers only"
    ],
    "correct": "The DRP has not been updated since an IT infrastructure upgrade"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following changeover techniques poses the GREATEST risk when moving application users from one system to another\"?",
    "options": [
      "Phased",
      "Pilot",
      "Parallel",
      "Direct"
    ],
    "correct": "Direct"
  },
  {
    "question": "An organization is modernizing its technology policy framework to demonstrate compliance with external industry standards Which of the following would be MOST useful Io an IS auditor for validating the outcome?",
    "options": [
      "Policy recommendations from a leading external consulting agency",
      "Inventory of the organization s approved policy exceptions",
      "Mapping of relevant standards against the organization\\x92s controls",
      "Benchmarking of internal standards against peer organizations"
    ],
    "correct": "Mapping of relevant standards against the organization\u0092s controls"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following provides the MOST useful information for performing a business impact analysis (BIA)?",
    "options": [
      "Policies for business procurement",
      "Inventory of relevant business processes",
      "Documentation of application configurations",
      "Results of business resumption planning efforts"
    ],
    "correct": "Inventory of relevant business processes"
  },
  {
    "question": "When initiating an IT project, which of the following should be completed FIRST?",
    "options": [
      "IT resource plan",
      "Feasibility Study",
      "Request for proposal (RFP)",
      "Milestone plan"
    ],
    "correct": "Feasibility Study"
  },
  {
    "question": "When reviewing the acquisition process for a new application, which of the following is MOST important to ensure was included in the request for proposal (RFP) process\u0092",
    "options": [
      "System development methodology",
      "Vendor key performance indicators (KPIs)",
      "User acceptance testing (UAT) plan",
      "Vendor financial stability"
    ],
    "correct": "User acceptance testing (UAT) plan"
  },
  {
    "question": "An external IS auditor is reviewing the continuous monitoring system for a large bank and notes several potential issues Which of the following would present the GREATEST concern regarding the reliability of the monitoring system\u0092",
    "options": [
      "The system results are not regularly reviewed by management",
      "The measurement method is periodically varied",
      "The monitoring system was configured by IT.",
      "The alert threshold is updated periodically"
    ],
    "correct": "The measurement method is periodically varied"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following would be the MOST useful metric for senior management to consider when reviewing the current project portfolio?",
    "options": [
      "Annualized loss expectancy (ALE) of the portfolio",
      "Expected return divided by the projected cost",
      "Total cost of each project",
      "Cost of projects divided by total IT cost"
    ],
    "correct": "Expected return divided by the projected cost"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following BEST explains how local area network (LAN) servers can contribute to a rapid spread of malware?",
    "options": [
      "The server's file sharing function facilitates the distribution of files and applications",
      "The server's users share applications and files",
      "The server's software is the prime target and is the first to be infected",
      "The servers are reimaged on startup"
    ],
    "correct": "The server's file sharing function facilitates the distribution of files and applications"
  },
  {
    "question": "What type of data analytics tool should be used to determine the correlation between the variables and a specific outcome?",
    "options": [
      "Prescriptive",
      "Diagnostic",
      "Predictive",
      "Descriptive"
    ],
    "correct": "Diagnostic"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is MOST appropriate for testing patches for business-critical applications?",
    "options": [
      "Regression testing",
      "User acceptance testing (UAT)",
      "Integrated test facility (ITF)",
      "Mapping software"
    ],
    "correct": "Regression testing"
  },
  {
    "question": "An IS auditor performed tests to evaluate the readiness of developed software for implementation. Which of the following test results BEST indicates that the software meets security requirements?",
    "options": [
      "Users can only perform tasks and functions assigned to their roles.",
      "The passwords meet both complexity and aging criteria.",
      "The software processes only required data types.",
      "Users are required to utilize encrypted connections."
    ],
    "correct": "Users can only perform tasks and functions assigned to their roles."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following will BEST ensure that archived electronic information of permanent importance remains accessible over time?",
    "options": [
      "Acquiring applications that emulate old software",
      "Performing preventive maintenance on old hardware",
      "Periodically backing up archived data",
      "Regularly migrating data to current technology"
    ],
    "correct": "Regularly migrating data to current technology"
  },
  {
    "question": "As part of an audit response, an auditee has concerns with the recommendations and is hesitant to implement them. Which of the following is the BEST course of action for the IS auditor?",
    "options": [
      "Accept the auditee\\x92s response and perform additional testing.",
      "Suggest hiring a third-party consultant to perform a current state assessment.",
      "Conduct further discussions with the auditee to develop a mitigation plan.",
      "Issue a final report without including the opinion of the auditee."
    ],
    "correct": "Conduct further discussions with the auditee to develop a mitigation plan."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the MOST important consideration when establishing vulnerability scanning on critical IT infrastructure?'",
    "options": [
      "The scanning will not degrade system performance.",
      "The scanning will be performed during non-peak hours.",
      "The scanning will be followed by penetration testing.",
      "The scanning will be cost-effective."
    ],
    "correct": "The scanning will be followed by penetration testing."
  },
  {
    "question": "An IT strategic plan that BEST leverages IT in achieving organizational goals will include:",
    "options": [
      "a comparison of future needs against current capabilities.",
      "enterprise architecture (EA) impacts.",
      "a risk-based ranking of projects,",
      "IT budgets linked to the organization's budget."
    ],
    "correct": "a comparison of future needs against current capabilities."
  },
  {
    "question": "A review of IT interface controls finds an organization does not have a process to identify and correct records that do not get transferred to the receiving system, which of the following is the IS auditor\u0092s BEST recommendation?",
    "options": [
      "Enable automatic encryption",
      "decryption",
      "and electronic signing of data files.",
      "Implement software to perform automatic reconciliations of data between systems.",
      "Automate the transfer of data between systems as much as is feasible,",
      "Have coders perform manual reconciliation of data between systems."
    ],
    "correct": "Automate the transfer of data between systems as much as is feasible,"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following provides the BEST evidence that system requirements are met when evaluating a project before implementation?",
    "options": [
      "Sign-off from senior management",
      "Integration testing results",
      "Regression testing results",
      "User acceptance testing (UAT) results"
    ],
    "correct": "User acceptance testing (UAT) results"
  },
  {
    "question": "A system administrator recently informed the IS auditor about the occurrence of several unsuccessful intrusion attempts from outside the organization. Which of the following is MOST effective in detecting such an intrusion?",
    "options": [
      "Using smart cards with one-time passwords",
      "Installing biometrics-based authentication",
      "Periodically reviewing log files",
      "Configuring the router as a firewall"
    ],
    "correct": "Periodically reviewing log files"
  },
  {
    "question": "During a follow-up audit, an IS auditor learns that some key management personnel have been replaced since the original audit, and current management has decided not to implement some previously accepted recommendations. What is the auditor's BEST course of action?",
    "options": [
      "Retest the control.",
      "Notify the chair of the audit committee,",
      "Close the audit finding.",
      "Notify the audit manager."
    ],
    "correct": "Notify the audit manager."
  },
  {
    "question": "An IS auditor is performing a follow-up audit for findings identified in an organization's user provisioning process. Which of the following is the MOST appropriate population to sample from when testing for remediation?",
    "options": [
      "All users provisioned after the final audit report was issued",
      "All users provisioned after management resolved the audit issue",
      "All users who have followed user provisioning processes provided by management",
      "All users provisioned after the finding was originally identified"
    ],
    "correct": "All users provisioned after management resolved the audit issue"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following IT service management activities is MOST likely to help with identifying the root cause of repeated instances of network latency?",
    "options": [
      "Change management",
      "Incident management",
      "Configuration management",
      "Problem management"
    ],
    "correct": "Problem management"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which type of review is MOST important to conduct when an IS auditor is informed that a recent internal exploitation of a bug has been discovered in a business application?",
    "options": [
      "Application security testing",
      "Server security audit",
      "Penetration testing",
      "Forensic audit"
    ],
    "correct": "Penetration testing"
  },
  {
    "question": "When reviewing the functionality of an intrusion detection system (IDS), the IS auditor should be MOST concerned if:",
    "options": [
      "legitimate packets blocked by the system have increased.",
      "detected events have increased.",
      "false positives have been reported.",
      "actual attacks have not been identified."
    ],
    "correct": "actual attacks have not been identified."
  },
  {
    "question": "The operations team of an organization has reported an IS security attack. Which of the following should be the FIRST step for the security incident response team?",
    "options": [
      "Prioritize resources for corrective action.",
      "Report results to management.",
      "Document lessons learned,",
      "Perform a damage assessment."
    ],
    "correct": "Perform a damage assessment."
  },
  {
    "question": "During an external review, an IS auditor observes an inconsistent approach in classifying system criticality within the organization. Which of the following should be recommended as the PRIMARY factor to determine system criticality?",
    "options": [
      "Recovery point objective (RPO)",
      "Maximum allowable downtime (MAD)",
      "Mean time to restore (MTTR)",
      "Key performance indicators (KPIs)"
    ],
    "correct": "Maximum allowable downtime (MAD)"
  },
  {
    "question": "When auditing the adequacy of a cooling system for a data center, which of the following is MOST important for the IS auditor to review?",
    "options": [
      "Disaster recovery plan (DRP) testing results",
      "Environmental performance metrics",
      "Facilities maintenance records",
      "Geographical location of the data center"
    ],
    "correct": "Environmental performance metrics"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the PRIMARY purpose of documenting audit objectives when preparing for an engagement?",
    "options": [
      "To help ensure maximum use of audit resources during the engagement",
      "To help prioritize and schedule auditee meetings",
      "To identify areas with relatively high probability of material problems",
      "To address the overall risk associated with the activity under review"
    ],
    "correct": "To identify areas with relatively high probability of material problems"
  },
  {
    "question": "To ensure confidentiality through the use of asymmetric encryption, a message is encrypted with which of the following?",
    "options": [
      "Recipient's public key",
      "Sender's public key",
      "Recipient\\x92s private key",
      "Sender\\x92s private key"
    ],
    "correct": "Recipient's public key"
  },
  {
    "question": "An organization has assigned two new IS auditors to audit a. new system implementation. One of the auditors has an IT-related degree, and one has a business degree. Which of the following is MOST important to meet the IS audit standard far proficiency?",
    "options": [
      "The standard is met as long as one member has a globally recognized audit certification.",
      "The standard is met as long as a supervisor reviews the new auditors' work.",
      "Team member assignments must be based on individual competencies.",
      "Technical co-sourcing must be used to help the new staff."
    ],
    "correct": "Team member assignments must be based on individual competencies."
  },
  {
    "question": "What type of control has been implemented when secure code reviews are conducted as part of a deployment program?",
    "options": [
      "Deterrent",
      "Corrective",
      "Monitoring",
      "Detective"
    ],
    "correct": "Detective"
  },
  {
    "question": "IT governance should be driven by:",
    "options": [
      "balanced scorecards.",
      "organizational strategies.",
      "business unit initiatives.",
      "policies and standards."
    ],
    "correct": "organizational strategies."
  },
  {
    "question": "As part of business continuity planning, which of the following is MOST important to assess when conducting a business impact analysis (BIA)?",
    "options": [
      "Critical applications in the cloud",
      "Risk appetite",
      "Recovery scenarios",
      "Completeness of critical asset inventory"
    ],
    "correct": "Completeness of critical asset inventory"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the PRIMARY advantage of using virtualization technology for corporate applications?",
    "options": [
      "Increased application performance",
      "Stronger data security",
      "Improved disaster recovery",
      "Better utilization of resources"
    ],
    "correct": "Better utilization of resources"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following would BEST guide an IS auditor when determining an appropriate lime to schedule the follow-up of agreed corrective actions for reported audit issues?",
    "options": [
      "Business management has completed the implementation of agreed actions on schedule.",
      "Regulators have announced a timeline for an inspection visit.",
      "Progress updates indicate that the implementation of agreed actions is on track.",
      "Sufficient time has elapsed since implementation to provide evidence of control operation."
    ],
    "correct": "Sufficient time has elapsed since implementation to provide evidence of control operation."
  },
  {
    "question": "A company runs a highly available image-processing application on Amazon EC2 instances in a single VPC. The EC2 instances run inside several subnets across multiple Availability Zones. The EC2 instances do not communicate with each other. However, the EC2 instances download images from Amazon S3 and upload images to Amazon S3 through a single NAT gateway. The company is concerned about data transfer charges. What is the MOST cost-effective way for the company to avoid regional data transfer charges?",
    "options": [
      "Launch the NAT gateway in each Availability Zone.",
      "Replace the NAT gateway with a NAT instance.",
      "Deploy a gateway VPC endpoint for Amazon S3.",
      "Provision an EC2 Dedicated Host to run the EC2 instances."
    ],
    "correct": "Deploy a gateway VPC endpoint for Amazon S3."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following criteria is MOST important for the successful delivery of benefits from an IT project?",
    "options": [
      "Ensuring that IT project managers have sign-off authority on the business case",
      "Quantifying the size of the software development effort required by the project",
      "Involving key stakeholders during the development and execution phases of the project",
      "Assessing the impact of changes to individuals and business units within the organization"
    ],
    "correct": "Involving key stakeholders during the development and execution phases of the project"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following would be of GREATEST concern to an IS auditor reviewing the feasibility study for a new application system?",
    "options": [
      "Conditions under which the system will operate are unclear.",
      "System requirements and expectations have not been clarified.",
      "The business case does not include well-defined strategic benefits.",
      "Security requirements have not been defined."
    ],
    "correct": "System requirements and expectations have not been clarified."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following poses the GREATEST risk to an organization related to system interfaces?",
    "options": [
      "Notifications of data transfers through the interfaces are not retained.",
      "Parts of the data transfer process are performed manually.",
      "There is no reliable inventory of system interfaces.",
      "There is no process documentation for some system interfaces."
    ],
    "correct": "There is no reliable inventory of system interfaces."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the PRIMARY reason for an IS auditor to meet with the auditee before communicating audit results to senior management?",
    "options": [
      "To identify new findings",
      "To recommend control enhancements",
      "To gain agreement on the findings",
      "To determine the timing of the next audit"
    ],
    "correct": "To gain agreement on the findings"
  },
  {
    "question": "An IS auditor is asked to review large organizations change management process. Which of the following practices presents the GREATEST risk?",
    "options": [
      "Change management tickets do not contain specific documentation.",
      "Emergency code changes are approved only after migration to production.",
      "A system administrator performs code migration on planned downtime.",
      "Transaction data changes can be made by a senior developer."
    ],
    "correct": "Transaction data changes can be made by a senior developer."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the MOST appropriate procedure for an organization to use when classifying data?",
    "options": [
      "Have the information security manager assign data classification levels.",
      "Review data classification questionnaires completed by data owners.",
      "Publish data classification templates on the corporate intranet,",
      "Use results from business impact analyses to classify data."
    ],
    "correct": "Review data classification questionnaires completed by data owners."
  },
  {
    "question": "An organization's strategy to source certain IT functions from a Software as a Service (SaaS) provider should be approved by the:",
    "options": [
      "chief risk officer (CRO).",
      "IT steering committee.",
      "IT operations manager.",
      "chief financial officer (CFO)."
    ],
    "correct": "IT steering committee."
  },
  {
    "question": "An IS auditor is evaluating the IT business planning process. Which of the following should be of GREATEST concern to the auditor?",
    "options": [
      "Business impact analysis (BIA) results are not included in the business case.",
      "Business case development is completed before strategic initiatives are finalized.",
      "End users are not involved in business case development.",
      "Several business cases are found to be based on a misdiagnosed problem."
    ],
    "correct": "Several business cases are found to be based on a misdiagnosed problem."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the MOST important prerequisite for the protection of physical information assets in a data center?",
    "options": [
      "Availability and testing of onsite backup generators",
      "Complete and accurate list of information assets that have been deployed",
      "Segregation of duties between staff ordering and staff receiving information assets",
      "Knowledge of the IT staff regarding data protection requirements"
    ],
    "correct": "Complete and accurate list of information assets that have been deployed"
  },
  {
    "question": "When an organization is developing data classification standards, it is MOST important to ensure the standards:",
    "options": [
      "align with the organization's segregation of duties requirements.",
      "align with the organization's IT capability maturity framework.",
      "are based on the business requirements for authentication of the information.",
      "are based on the business requirements for confidentiality of the information."
    ],
    "correct": "are based on the business requirements for confidentiality of the information."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following should be an IS auditor's GREATEST concern when assessing an IT service configuration database?",
    "options": [
      "The database is executable for all users.",
      "The database is write-accessible for all users.",
      "The database is not encrypted at rest.",
      "The database is read-accessible for all users."
    ],
    "correct": "The database is write-accessible for all users."
  },
  {
    "question": "An organization's sensitive data is stored in a cloud computing environment and is encrypted. Which of the following findings should be of GREATEST concern to an IS auditor?",
    "options": [
      "The cloud vendor does not have multi-regional presence.",
      "Symmetric keys are used for encryption.",
      "The encryption keys are not kept under dual control.",
      "Data encryption keys are accessible to the service provider."
    ],
    "correct": "Data encryption keys are accessible to the service provider."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the MOST appropriate responsibility of an IS auditor involved in a data center renovation project?",
    "options": [
      "Performing independent reviews of responsible parties engaged in the project",
      "Shortlisting vendors to perform renovations",
      "Implementing data center operational controls",
      "Ensuring the project progresses as scheduled and milestones are achieved"
    ],
    "correct": "Performing independent reviews of responsible parties engaged in the project"
  },
  {
    "question": "An organization that has decided to approve the use of end-user computing (EUC) should FIRST ensure:",
    "options": [
      "a business impact analysis (BIA) is conducted.",
      "EUC controls are reviewed.",
      "an EUC policy is developed.",
      "EUC use cases are assessed and documented."
    ],
    "correct": "an EUC policy is developed."
  },
  {
    "question": "During an emergency change management audit, an IS auditor notes that one of the changes sampled was a standard change, which follows a different process. What should the auditor do NEXT?",
    "options": [
      "Redefine population and sample changes accordingly.",
      "Notify auditee management of the finding.",
      "Obtain evidence that the change was approved.",
      "Perform supplemental sampling of standard changes."
    ],
    "correct": "Redefine population and sample changes accordingly."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following should be done FIRST when a computer is compromised?",
    "options": [
      "Run anti-malware software.",
      "Disconnect the power source.",
      "Disconnect it from the network.",
      "Copy the contents of the hard drive."
    ],
    "correct": "Disconnect it from the network."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following observations should be of GREATEST concern to an IS auditor reviewing a recently implemented database system that automates the administration of clients' pension plans at a financial institution?",
    "options": [
      "Clients' consent was not obtained for the intended processing of their personal data.",
      "Policies and procedures related to the retention of client data have not been documented.",
      "A privacy impact assessment was not conducted prior to the implementation.",
      "Clients are able to view their accounts and plan details via a web portal."
    ],
    "correct": "Clients' consent was not obtained for the intended processing of their personal data."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following would be of GREATEST concern to an IS auditor reviewing an organization\u0092s newly implemented vendor management process for potential fraud?",
    "options": [
      "Different people oversee vendor performance and approve payment of their invoices.",
      "The same person who oversees a vendor's performance approves payment for their invoices.",
      "Vendors create and edit their own profiles through a portal.",
      "Accounts payable clerks create and edit vendor profiles."
    ],
    "correct": "The same person who oversees a vendor's performance approves payment for their invoices."
  },
  {
    "question": "Capacity management BEST enables organizations to:",
    "options": [
      "establish the capacity of network communication links.",
      "forecast technology trends.",
      "determine business transaction volumes.",
      "identify which components need to be upgraded."
    ],
    "correct": "determine business transaction volumes."
  },
  {
    "question": "An IS auditor identifies a process deficiency involving multiple departments. None of the departments will accept ownership of the deficiency or the remediation efforts. What should the auditor do FIRST?",
    "options": [
      "Document the deficiency in the audit report and let management determine who is responsible.",
      "Facilitate a meeting with affected parties to discuss potential cooperative remediation efforts.",
      "Report each party's portion of the deficiency and their respective remediation plans separately",
      "Continue negotiations with both parties until ownership of the deficiency and remediation is determined."
    ],
    "correct": "Facilitate a meeting with affected parties to discuss potential cooperative remediation efforts."
  },
  {
    "question": "Management has agreed to move the organization's data center due to recent flood map changes in its current location. Which risk response has been adopted?",
    "options": [
      "Risk acceptance",
      "Risk transfer",
      "Risk elimination",
      "Risk avoidance"
    ],
    "correct": "Risk avoidance"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the MOST important consideration of any disaster response plan?",
    "options": [
      "Lost revenue",
      "Adequate resource capacity",
      "IT asset protection",
      "Personnel safety"
    ],
    "correct": "Personnel safety"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is MOST important for an IS auditor to review when evaluating the completeness of an organization's personally identifiable information (Pll) inventory?",
    "options": [
      "Data encryption",
      "Dataflows",
      "Data retention",
      "Data ownership"
    ],
    "correct": "Data encryption"
  },
  {
    "question": "An IS auditor is reviewing an organization's plan to migrate a legacy database platform to a cloud-based database service. Which of the following steps is MOST important during the migration to preserve data integrity?",
    "options": [
      "Ensure data in the legacy platform has been normalized.",
      "Implement new access controls and user authentication on the cloud.",
      "Run the application in parallel for a determined period of time.",
      "Establish data validation checks during the migration process."
    ],
    "correct": "Establish data validation checks during the migration process."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the GREATEST advantage of maintaining an internal IS audit function within an organization?",
    "options": [
      "Ability to negotiate recommendations with management",
      "Increased IS audit staff visibility and availability throughout the year",
      "Better understanding of the business and processes",
      "Increased independence and impartiality of recommendations"
    ],
    "correct": "Better understanding of the business and processes"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is MOST likely to be a project deliverable of an agile software development methodology?",
    "options": [
      "Automated software programming routines",
      "Extensive project documentation",
      "Rapidly created working prototypes",
      "Strictly managed software requirements baselines"
    ],
    "correct": "Rapidly created working prototypes"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following would BEST prevent an arbitrary application of a patch?",
    "options": [
      "Established maintenance windows",
      "Network based access controls",
      "Change management",
      "Database access control"
    ],
    "correct": "Change management"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following environments is BEST used for copying data and transformation into a compatible data warehouse format?",
    "options": [
      "Staging",
      "Testing",
      "Replication",
      "Development"
    ],
    "correct": "Staging"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following can be used to implement dual-factor authentication?",
    "options": [
      "An RFID card and proximity reader used for access to the computer room",
      "A physical key and nondescript electronic-swipe employee badge used for access to the building",
      "A personalized keypad access code and combination lock to the server room",
      "A fully functional smart card and user-specific PIN used for access to the network room"
    ],
    "correct": "A fully functional smart card and user-specific PIN used for access to the network room"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the GREATEST concern when applying emergency patches?",
    "options": [
      "A change record may not be properly maintained",
      "Documented approvals may not be required before applying the emergency patch ",
      "Patch-related risk may not be adequately assessed.",
      "Temporary administrative permissions may be needed to apply patches"
    ],
    "correct": "Patch-related risk may not be adequately assessed."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the PRIMARY reason to involve IS auditors in the software acquisition process?",
    "options": [
      "To help ensure hardware and operating system requirements are considered",
      "To help ensure proposed contracts and service level agreements (SLAs) address key elements",
      "To help ensure adequate controls to address common threats and risks are considered",
      "To help ensure the project management process complies with policies and procedures"
    ],
    "correct": "To help ensure adequate controls to address common threats and risks are considered"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is MOST important for an IS auditor to verify when evaluating an organization's data conversion and infrastructure migration plan7",
    "options": [
      "Strategic goals have been considered",
      "A rollback plan is included",
      "A migration steering committee has been formed",
      "A code check review is included"
    ],
    "correct": "A rollback plan is included"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is MOST important to ensure when developing an effective security awareness program?",
    "options": [
      "Phishing exercises are conducted post-training",
      "Outcome metrics for the program are established",
      "Security threat scenarios are included in the program content.",
      "Training personnel are information security professionals"
    ],
    "correct": "Outcome metrics for the program are established"
  },
  {
    "question": "In an IT organization where many responsibilities are shared, which of the following is the BEST control for detecting unauthorized data changes?",
    "options": [
      "Data changes are logged in an outside application",
      "Users are required to periodically rotate responsibilities",
      "Data changes are independently reviewed by another group",
      "Segregation of duties conflicts are periodically reviewed."
    ],
    "correct": "Data changes are independently reviewed by another group"
  },
  {
    "question": "A bank performed minor changes to the interest calculation computer program Which of the following techniques would provide the STRONGEST evidence to determine whether the interest calculations are correct?",
    "options": [
      "Parallel simulation using audit software",
      "Manual verification of a sample of the results",
      "Review of the quality assurance (QA) test results",
      "Source code review"
    ],
    "correct": "Manual verification of a sample of the results"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following practices is MOST helpful in eliminating potential bias during the vendor proposal review process?",
    "options": [
      "A procurement professional is the point of contact for all vendors responding with proposals",
      "The services of an internal or external auditor are available when vendor proposals are reviewed",
      "Internal software development teams are not permitted to provide proposals to the project",
      "The project sponsor is available to all vendors to explain proposal requirements"
    ],
    "correct": "A procurement professional is the point of contact for all vendors responding with proposals"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following audit procedures would provide the BEST assurance that an application program is functioning as designed?",
    "options": [
      "Reviewing program documentation",
      "Interviewing business management ",
      "Using a continuous auditing module ",
      "Confirming accounts"
    ],
    "correct": "Using a continuous auditing module"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following provides the BEST method for maintaining the security of corporate applications pushed to employee-owned mobile devices?",
    "options": [
      "Disabling unnecessary network connectivity options",
      "Requiring security awareness training for mobile users",
      "Enabling remote data destruction capabilities",
      "Implementing mobile device management (MDM)"
    ],
    "correct": "Implementing mobile device management (MDM)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is MOST important for an IS auditor to review during an audit of an automated continuous monitoring process being used by the finance department?",
    "options": [
      "Dual control and approvals embedded in processes",
      "Resiliency of the monitoring service",
      "Configuration of the monitoring tool",
      "Management sign-off of test documentation"
    ],
    "correct": "Configuration of the monitoring tool"
  },
  {
    "question": "When assessing whether an organization's IT performance measures are comparable to other organizations in the same industry, which of the following would be MOST helpful to review?",
    "options": [
      "Balanced scorecard",
      "Utilization reports",
      "IT governance frameworks",
      "Benchmarking surveys"
    ],
    "correct": "Benchmarking surveys"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following practices is MOST helpful in preventing incidents as a result of implemented software changes?",
    "options": [
      "Evidence of successful changes are documented",
      "Standardized procedures are used for prompt handling of changes",
      "Proposed changes are tested by stakeholders prior to implementation",
      "Personnel obtain senior management approval prior to implementing changes"
    ],
    "correct": "Proposed changes are tested by stakeholders prior to implementation"
  },
  {
    "question": "The PRIMARY benefit of using a statistical sampling method in an IS audit is to",
    "options": [
      "mitigate audit risk.",
      "objectively quantify the probability of error",
      "determine the tolerable error rate",
      "avoid residual risk"
    ],
    "correct": "objectively quantify the probability of error"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following security information and event management (SIEM) issues should be of MOST concern to an IS auditor?",
    "options": [
      "Some of the log sources have proprietary log formats",
      "The log sources include a wide range of operating systems and technologies",
      "Log source times are not synchronized to a common time source",
      "Some of the log sources generate a large number of log events"
    ],
    "correct": "Log source times are not synchronized to a common time source"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the MOST efficient control to reduce the risk associated with a systems administrator having network administrator responsibilities?",
    "options": [
      "The administrator must sign a due diligence agreement",
      "The administrator will be subject to unannounced audits",
      "The administrator will need to request additional approval for critical changes",
      "The administrator must obtain temporary access to make critical changes"
    ],
    "correct": "The administrator must obtain temporary access to make critical changes"
  },
  {
    "question": "An organization is establishing a steering committee for the implementation of a new enterprise resource planning (ERP) system that uses Agile project management methodology What is the MOST important criterion for the makeup of this committee?",
    "options": [
      "Senior management representation",
      "ERP implementation experience",
      "Agile project management experience",
      "Ability to meet the time commitment required"
    ],
    "correct": "Senior management representation"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is MOST important to the effectiveness of smoke detectors installed in a data processing facility?",
    "options": [
      "Detectors have the correct industry certification",
      "Detectors are linked to dry pipe fire suppression systems",
      "Detectors trigger audible alarms when activated",
      "Detectors are linked to wet pipe fire suppression systems"
    ],
    "correct": "Detectors trigger audible alarms when activated"
  },
  {
    "question": "An IS audit team is evaluating documentation of the most recent application user access review It is determined that the user list was not system generated Which of the following should be of MOST concern?",
    "options": [
      "Confidentiality of the user list",
      "Timeliness of the user list review",
      "Completeness of the user list",
      "Availability of the user list"
    ],
    "correct": "Completeness of the user list"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following fire suppression methods is MOST effective for use in a data center?",
    "options": [
      "Dry chemical compounds",
      "Wet-pipe water sprinkler system",
      "Inert gases",
      "Dry-pipe water sprinkler system"
    ],
    "correct": "Dry-pipe water sprinkler system"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the MOST effective audit approach to verify whether the projected benefits described in an IT project's business case are realistic?",
    "options": [
      "Review of the cost-benefit analysis performed by management",
      "Review of mitigation plans against business risk",
      "Comparison against industry business practices",
      "Interviews with business stakeholders"
    ],
    "correct": "Review of the cost-benefit analysis performed by management"
  },
  {
    "question": "When reviewing hard disk utilization reports, an IS auditor observes that utilization is routinely above 95% Which of the following should be the GREATEST concern to the IS auditor\"?",
    "options": [
      "Consistency",
      "Data security",
      "Denial of service (DoS) attacks",
      "Availability"
    ],
    "correct": "Availability"
  },
  {
    "question": "When auditing an organization's procurement process, which of the following observations should be of MOST concern to an IS auditor\"?",
    "options": [
      "Thresholds for requesting and approving payments for purchase requests have not been established",
      "The procurement manager is new to the organization",
      "Purchasing procedures and processes have not been updated during the past two years",
      "Contracts can be approved after expenses have been incurred"
    ],
    "correct": "Contracts can be approved after expenses have been incurred"
  },
  {
    "question": "An IS auditor is summarizing findings from a review of a key customer relationship management (CRM) system implementation Which of the following findings should be assigned the HIGHEST priority?",
    "options": [
      "The project failed to meet the sponsor's objectives.",
      "The post-implementation review was not completed",
      "User acceptance testing (UAT) was not completed",
      "Changes in the project schedule were not documented"
    ],
    "correct": "The project failed to meet the sponsor's objectives."
  },
  {
    "question": "An organization performs both full and incremental database backups Which of the following will BEST enable full restoration in the event of the destruction of the data center?",
    "options": [
      "Rotate all backups to an offsite location daily",
      "Secure alternative data centers",
      "Enable a remote workforce capability",
      "Require manager to take home weekly backups"
    ],
    "correct": "Rotate all backups to an offsite location daily"
  },
  {
    "question": "The manager of a business unit being audited is concerned that a line of inquiry posed by an external IS auditor exceeds the scope of the audit Which of the following resources would be MOST helpful to determine if the concern is valid?",
    "options": [
      "Statement of work (SOW)",
      "Audit charter",
      "Audit testing plan",
      "Risk assessment results"
    ],
    "correct": "Statement of work (SOW)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the MOST important consideration when evaluating the data retention policy for a global organization with regional offices in multiple countries",
    "options": [
      "The policy aligns with corporate policies and practices.",
      "The policy aligns with business goals and objectives.",
      "The policy aligns with local laws and regulations",
      "The policy aligns with global best practices"
    ],
    "correct": "The policy aligns with local laws and regulations"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who would provide an IS auditor with the MOST helpful input during an interview to determine whether business requirements for an application were met?",
    "options": [
      "User management",
      "Project management",
      "Project sponsors",
      "Senior management"
    ],
    "correct": "User management"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the PRIMARY benefit of conducting control self-assessments (CSAs)?",
    "options": [
      "Reduction in inherent risk",
      "Management of control costs",
      "Early detection of residual risk",
      "Reduction in external audit fees"
    ],
    "correct": "Early detection of residual risk"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following would BEST enhance the capability of a web server to accommodate a significant increase in web traffic?",
    "options": [
      "Additional network connections",
      "Solid state drives",
      "Virtualized environments",
      "Elastic cloud architecture"
    ],
    "correct": "Elastic cloud architecture"
  },
  {
    "question": "An IS auditor reviewing the IS strategic planning process should FIRST review the:',",
    "options": [
      "current technology trends.",
      "existing information technology environment.",
      "business continuity strategy.",
      "business plan."
    ],
    "correct": "existing information technology environment."
  },
  {
    "question": "An organization has moved to a thin client architecture for all its causer computing (EUC) Which of the following would be of GREATEST concern when scoping a new audit?",
    "options": [
      "Availability",
      "Scalability",
      "Concurrency",
      "Portability"
    ],
    "correct": "Availability"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following should an IS auditor verify FIRST when evaluating data quality and life cycle management?",
    "options": [
      "Proper version control for data has been implemented and tested",
      "Funding has been approved and allocated for data storage and preservation.",
      "The data audit framework methodology has been tested before approval",
      "Guidance is available for the creation management",
      "and preservation of data"
    ],
    "correct": "Guidance is available for the creation management, and preservation of data"
  },
  {
    "question": "An IS auditor has been asked to participate in the creation of an organization's formal business continuity program Which of the following would MOST impair auditor independence?",
    "options": [
      "Implementing disaster recovery test scenarios",
      "Determining system criticality",
      "Participating on the business continuity committee",
      "Facilitating the business impact analysis (BIA)"
    ],
    "correct": "Implementing disaster recovery test scenarios"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following findings should be of GREATEST concern during an audit of IT governance and management?",
    "options": [
      "The IT strategy development process is not documented",
      "There is no IT representation in business strategy committee meetings.",
      "The organization is not aligned with an international IT control standard",
      "There is no chief information security officer (CISO) position."
    ],
    "correct": "There is no IT representation in business strategy committee meetings."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is MOST important for an IS auditor to review when evaluating a business case for increasing the capacity of a critical application?'",
    "options": [
      "Accuracy of projected return on investment (ROI) calculations",
      "Historical and future volumes of processed transactions",
      "Sufficient budget allocation for acquiring new hardware and software",
      "Functional and technical specifications"
    ],
    "correct": "Historical and future volumes of processed transactions"
  },
  {
    "question": "An IS auditor plans to review all access attempts to a video-monitored and proximity card-controlled communications room Which of the following would be MOST useful to the auditor?",
    "options": [
      "Access card allocation records",
      "Alarm system with CCTV",
      "Access control log",
      "Security incident log"
    ],
    "correct": "Access control log"
  },
  {
    "question": "When verifying the effectiveness of an organization's provisioning process, which sampling technique is MOST appropriate to use'?",
    "options": [
      "Haphazard sampling",
      "Random sampling",
      "Judgmental sampling",
      "Stop-or-go sampling"
    ],
    "correct": "Judgmental sampling"
  },
  {
    "question": "In an online application, which of the following would provide the MOST information about the transaction audit trail?",
    "options": [
      "Source code documentation",
      "File layouts",
      "Data classification schema",
      "System/process flowchart"
    ],
    "correct": "System/process flowchart"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following presents the GREATEST risk to the successful implementation of an IT project'?",
    "options": [
      "The budget is not formally approved by the project sponsor",
      "Limited resources are available.",
      "Business requirements are not defined",
      "The project sponsor does not attend steering committee meetings."
    ],
    "correct": "Business requirements are not defined"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the BEST IS audit procedure to provide assurance against internal fraud within an organization's payroll processes?",
    "options": [
      "Interview the payroll manager to obtain a detailed process workflow",
      "Review management's approval of payroll system changes.",
      "Review management's validation of payroll payment recipients",
      "Compare employee head count to payroll expense"
    ],
    "correct": "Compare employee head count to payroll expense"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following control objectives is BEST addressed by using a virtual private network (VPN)?",
    "options": [
      "Confidentiality",
      "Availability",
      "Nonrepudiation",
      "Completeness"
    ],
    "correct": "Confidentiality"
  },
  {
    "question": "To enable a fair and equitable selection process, a request for proposal (RFP) should include a description of:",
    "options": [
      "Details of existing IT infrastructure.",
      "budgeted costs for the solution.",
      "the vendor\\x92s market share",
      "evaluation criteria and methodology."
    ],
    "correct": "evaluation criteria and methodology."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which type of data analytics can be used to identify invalid data, extreme values, or linear correlations between data elements?",
    "options": [
      "Predictive",
      "Prescriptive",
      "Descriptive",
      "Exploratory"
    ],
    "correct": "Predictive"
  },
  {
    "question": "An IS auditor discovers that the account of a terminated application engineer is still enabled on a core business application. Further inquiry revealed that the engineer designed several business-critical middleware applications that require the existence of the engineer's user account to function. What would be the auditor's BEST recommendation to management?",
    "options": [
      "Disable the user account and assign critical roles to a service account.",
      "Provide staff with secure coding training.",
      "Ensure the user account is not used for other systems and applications.",
      "Develop a key employee succession plan."
    ],
    "correct": "Ensure the user account is not used for other systems and applications."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following findings would be of GREATEST concern when auditing an organization's end-user computing (EUC)?",
    "options": [
      "Inability to monitor EUC audit logs and activities",
      "Reduced oversight by the IT department",
      "Inconsistency of patching processes being followed",
      "Errors flowed through to financial statements"
    ],
    "correct": "Errors flowed through to financial statements"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following BEST indicates to an IS auditor that an organization handles emergency changes appropriately and transparently?",
    "options": [
      "Change management controls are retroactively applied.",
      "Emergency changes are applied to production libraries immediately.",
      "Special logon IDs are used to grant programmers permanent access to the production environment",
      "The application operations manual contains procedures to ensure emergency fixes do not compromise system integrity."
    ],
    "correct": "The application operations manual contains procedures to ensure emergency fixes do not compromise system integrity."
  },
  {
    "question": "An IS auditor is reviewing an organization that performs backups on local database servers every two weeks and does not have a formal policy to govern data backup and restoration procedures Which of the following findings presents the GREATEST risk to the organization?",
    "options": [
      "Absence of a data backup policy",
      "Insufficient data backup frequency",
      "Lack of offsite data backups",
      "Lack of periodic data restoration testing"
    ],
    "correct": "Lack of offsite data backups"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the BEST way to determine that transaction updates were successfully completed by a batch job?",
    "options": [
      "Reviewing a copy of the script for the batch job",
      "Performing data analytics against the complete transaction log",
      "Reviewing transaction batch job history",
      "the following day",
      "Obtaining process owner confirmation that the job was completed"
    ],
    "correct": "Performing data analytics against the complete transaction log"
  },
  {
    "question": "An IS auditor is scheduled to conduct a follow-up and is told by operational management that new priorities prevented them from implementing the action plan Management plans to address the audit issues after the next quarter Whal should be the auditor's NEXT course of action?",
    "options": [
      "Report management's lack of action to the audit committee",
      "Defer the follow-up engagement for later in the year",
      "Conduct the follow-up engagement as scheduled.",
      "Assess the risk of the delayed implementation."
    ],
    "correct": "Assess the risk of the delayed implementation."
  },
  {
    "question": "Shortly after a system was deployed into production, it was identified that some key scenarios were not tested during user acceptance testing (DAT) Which of the following is the GREATEST concern with this situation?",
    "options": [
      "System functions may not meet business requirements.",
      "The system may have gone into production with defects",
      "Extra funding may be required to complete the testing.",
      "Significant security risks may not have been assessed."
    ],
    "correct": "System functions may not meet business requirements."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following findings would be of GREATEST concern when reviewing project risk management practices?",
    "options": [
      "There are no formal milestone sign-offs.",
      "Ongoing issues are not formally tracked",
      "Qualitative risk analyses have not been updated",
      "Project management software is not being used"
    ],
    "correct": "Ongoing issues are not formally tracked"
  },
  {
    "question": "During a change management audit, anis auditor identifies that some changes were implemented in the production environment without user acceptance testing (LIAT). Which of the following is the auditor's BEST course of action?",
    "options": [
      "Perform post-implementation testing to verify that the changes do not impact financial data.",
      "Recommend the IT manager roll back the changes and continue with the audit.",
      "Document the finding and explain the risk of implementing changes without appropriate testing.",
      "Postpone the audit until adequate LIAT can be performed"
    ],
    "correct": "Document the finding and explain the risk of implementing changes without appropriate testing."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the BEST indicator that a third-party vendor adheres to the controls required by the organization?",
    "options": [
      "Regular independent assessment of the vendor",
      "Review of monthly performance reports submitted by the vendor",
      "Certifications maintained by the vendor",
      "Substantive log file review of the vendor\\x92s system"
    ],
    "correct": "Regular independent assessment of the vendor"
  },
  {
    "question": "An IS audit report highlighting inadequate network internal controls is challenged because no serious incident has ever occurred. Which of the following actions performed during the audit would have BEST supported the findings?",
    "options": [
      "Compliance testing",
      "Threat risk assessment",
      "Penetration testing",
      "Vulnerability assessment"
    ],
    "correct": "Vulnerability assessment"
  },
  {
    "question": "An organization's sensitive data is stored in a cloud computing environment and is encrypted Which of the following findings should be of GREATEST concern to an IS auditor9",
    "options": [
      "The cloud vendor does not have multi-regional presence.",
      "Symmetric keys are used for encryption",
      "The encryption keys are not kept under dual control.",
      "Data encryption keys are accessible to the service provider."
    ],
    "correct": "Data encryption keys are accessible to the service provider."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following should be the PRIMARY focus when communicating an IS audit issue to management?",
    "options": [
      "The nature",
      "extent",
      "and timing of subsequent audit follow-up",
      "A detailed solution for resolving the issue",
      "The risk to which the organization is exposed due to the issue",
      "How the issue was found and who bears responsibility"
    ],
    "correct": "The risk to which the organization is exposed due to the issue"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following potential scenarios is MOST likely to result in audit risk?",
    "options": [
      "Management may have differing opinions of audit results.",
      "Audit files may be lost due to a ransomware attack.",
      "New auditor hiring may be delayed due to budget cuts.",
      "Sampling methods may not detect a material error."
    ],
    "correct": "Sampling methods may not detect a material error."
  },
  {
    "question": "During an audit of a data center with updated technology, the auditee indicates that environmental controls are the same as those used in the previous environment The IS auditor should FIRST",
    "options": [
      "recommend changes to the maintenance schedule.",
      "determine whether the controls are active.",
      "lest selected controls",
      "review equipment specifications"
    ],
    "correct": "review equipment specifications"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following would be an IS auditor's BEST recommendation to senior management when several IT initiatives are found to be misaligned with the organization's strategy.",
    "options": [
      "Reassess the return on investment (ROI) for the IT initiatives",
      "",
      "Reassess IT initiatives that do not map to business strategies ",
      "Define key performance indicators (KPIs) for IT",
      "Modify IT initiatives that do not map to business strategies."
    ],
    "correct": "Reassess IT initiatives that do not map to business strategies"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the MOST important consideration when designing a risk-based incident response management program?",
    "options": [
      "Monitoring recurring low-risk events",
      "Testing and updating the incident response plan annually",
      "Minimizing false-positive and false-negative alerts",
      "Assigning roles and responsibilities"
    ],
    "correct": "Minimizing false-positive and false-negative alerts"
  },
  {
    "question": "The PRIMARY objective of a follow-up audit is to:",
    "options": [
      "verify compliance with policies",
      "determine adequacy of actions taken on recommendations.",
      "evaluate whether the risk profile has changed",
      "assess the appropriateness of recommendations."
    ],
    "correct": "determine adequacy of actions taken on recommendations."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following can BEST reduce the impact of a long-term power failure?",
    "options": [
      "Redundant power source",
      "Battery bank",
      "Emergency power-off switches",
      "Power conditioning unit"
    ],
    "correct": "Redundant power source"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following would be of GREATEST concern to an IS auditor reviewing the feasibility study for a new application system",
    "options": [
      "System requirements and expectations have not been clarified",
      "Conditions under which the system will operate are unclear.",
      "Security requirements have not been defined.",
      "The business case does not include well-defined strategic benefits."
    ],
    "correct": "System requirements and expectations have not been clarified"
  },
  {
    "question": "An IT strategic plan that BEST leverages IT in achieving organizational goals will include",
    "options": [
      "a comparison of future needs against current capabilities",
      "enterprise architecture (EA) impacts",
      "IT budgets linked to the organization's budget.",
      "a risk-based ranking of projects."
    ],
    "correct": "enterprise architecture (EA) impacts"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the MOST effective way to manage contractors' access to a data center",
    "options": [
      "Verification of visitor identification",
      "Management approval of visitor access",
      "Escort requirement for visitor access",
      "Badge identification worn by visitors"
    ],
    "correct": "Escort requirement for visitor access"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is MOST beneficial to executive management in achieving IT and business alignment?",
    "options": [
      "Benchmarking",
      "Performance measurement",
      "Balanced scorecard",
      "Risk assessment"
    ],
    "correct": "Balanced scorecard"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which type of data analytics can be used to identify invalid data, extreme values, or linear correlations between data elements?",
    "options": [
      "Predictive",
      "Prescriptive",
      "Descriptive",
      "Exploratory"
    ],
    "correct": "Predictive"
  },
  {
    "question": "When multiple IT projects have to be run simultaneously for a data loss prevention (DLP) initiative, which of the following should be introduced to BEST minimize the associated risk?",
    "options": [
      "Portfolio management",
      "Resource management",
      "Program management",
      "Change management"
    ],
    "correct": "Program management"
  },
  {
    "question": "During a follow-up engagement, an IS auditor confirms evidence of a problem that was not an issue in the original audit. Which of the following is the auditor's BEST course of action:",
    "options": [
      "Report the risk to management in the follow-up report",
      "Report only on the areas within the scope of the follow-up.",
      "Include the evidence as part of a future audit,",
      "Expand the follow-up scope to include examining the evidence."
    ],
    "correct": "Expand the follow-up scope to include examining the evidence."
  },
  {
    "question": "An IS auditor reviewing the IS strategic planning process should FIRST review the:",
    "options": [
      "current technology trends.",
      "existing information technology environment.",
      "business continuity strategy",
      "business plan"
    ],
    "correct": "existing information technology environment."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following would BEST enhance the capability of a web server to accommodate a significant increase in web traffic?",
    "options": [
      "Additional network connections",
      "Solid state drives",
      "Virtualized environments",
      "Elastic cloud architecture"
    ],
    "correct": "Elastic cloud architecture"
  },
  {
    "question": "An IS auditor is reviewing vulnerability scanning results of an organization's critical systems. Which of the following is the BEST way to validate that the vulnerabilities have been remediated?",
    "options": [
      "Re-scan the vulnerable systems.",
      "Review change management documentation for remediation.",
      "Review patch management documentation.",
      "Interview owners of vulnerability scanning systems for evidence."
    ],
    "correct": "Review change management documentation for remediation."
  },
  {
    "question": "An IT asset management review finds that routers and switches are not sanitized before disposal. What is the GREATEST concern with this situation?",
    "options": [
      "Configuration files may be extracted from the devices and compromise a network's security.",
      "Confidential data files may be extracted from the devices and result in a privacy breach.",
      "Staff are not following the organization's sanitization policies and procedures.",
      "Sanitization is not part of the IT department\\x92s security awareness training program."
    ],
    "correct": "Confidential data files may be extracted from the devices and result in a privacy breach."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following practices is MOST helpful in preventing new incidents from occurring as a result of a recent patch installation?",
    "options": [
      "Risk analyses are performed to justify the installation of security patches.",
      "Security patches are tested prior to installation on the organization's equipment.",
      "Tools are used to assess patch updates prior to installation of security patches.",
      "Security patches require senior management approval prior to installation."
    ],
    "correct": "Security patches are tested prior to installation on the organization's equipment."
  },
  {
    "question": "An IS auditor performs an audit of physical access controls in an organization that uses RFID access cards at entrances. Which of the following findings poses the GREATEST risk?",
    "options": [
      "Card readers are not connected to a centralized authorization server.",
      "Access cards for one-day guests do not display the holder's photo.",
      "Card readers do not have a backup battery to cope with power outages.",
      "Security is not alerted after three failed access attempts."
    ],
    "correct": "Card readers are not connected to a centralized authorization server."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following should be the PRIMARY consideration when establishing audit objectives?",
    "options": [
      "Industry best practices",
      "Assessment of prior audits",
      "Organizational risk",
      "Audit risk"
    ],
    "correct": "Organizational risk"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following user actions poses the GREATEST risk for inadvertently introducing malware into a local network?",
    "options": [
      "Downloading a file from an enterprise file share",
      "Opening an email attachment from an external account",
      "Viewing a hypertext markup language (HTML) document",
      "Uploading a file onto an internal server"
    ],
    "correct": "Opening an email attachment from an external account"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following fire suppression methods is MOST effective for use in a data center?",
    "options": [
      "Inert gases",
      "Dry chemical compounds",
      "Dry-pipe water sprinkler system",
      "Wet-pipe water sprinkler system"
    ],
    "correct": "Dry-pipe water sprinkler system"
  },
  {
    "question": "An IS auditor finds that a new network connection allows communication between the Internet and the internal enterprise resource planning (ERP) system. Which of the following is the PRIMARY business impact to include when presenting this observation to management?",
    "options": [
      "An increase to the threat landscape",
      "A decrease in data quality in the ERP system",
      "An increase in potential fines from regulators",
      "A decrease in network performance"
    ],
    "correct": "An increase to the threat landscape"
  },
  {
    "question": "An IS auditor recommends that the most recent patches be applied to all virtualized devices. Management objects because it does not consider the recommendation feasible. Which of the following is the auditors BEST course of action?",
    "options": [
      "Insist that management create an action plan to address this risk.",
      "Conduct a cost-benefit analysis to determine the feasibility.",
      "Work with management to determine an acceptable alternative action plan.",
      "Perform additional analysis to demonstrate the actual impact of missing patches."
    ],
    "correct": "Work with management to determine an acceptable alternative action plan."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following findings related to segregation of duties should be of GREATEST concern to an IS auditor?",
    "options": [
      "The person who edits source code also has write access to production.",
      "The person who creates new user accounts also modifies user access levels.",
      "The person who administers servers is also part of the infrastructure management team.",
      "The person who tests source code also approves changes."
    ],
    "correct": "The person who edits source code also has write access to production."
  },
  {
    "question": "An IS auditor noted that management authorized the implementation of patches on IT infrastructure components without evaluation. The auditor's GREATEST concern should be that the patches were not evaluated for:",
    "options": [
      "compliance with release management.",
      "alignment with the data reference model.",
      "impact on operational costs.",
      "impact on the current IT environment."
    ],
    "correct": "impact on the current IT environment."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following should be the PRIMARY purpose of conducting tabletop exercises when reviewing a security incident response plan?",
    "options": [
      "To gather documentation for responding to security audit inquiries",
      "To provide efficiencies for alignment with incident response test scenarios",
      "To confirm that technology is in place to support the incident response plan",
      "To determine process improvement options for the incident response plan"
    ],
    "correct": "To determine process improvement options for the incident response plan"
  },
  {
    "question": "Data centers that want to prevent unauthorized personnel from entering during a power outage should ensure external access doors:",
    "options": [
      "are alarmed and monitored.",
      "operate in fail-safe mode.",
      "operate in fail-secure mode.",
      "have physical key backup."
    ],
    "correct": "operate in fail-secure mode."
  },
  {
    "question": "At the conclusion of an IS audit, senior management decides to accept the risk of not correcting one of the reported issues. In the auditor's opinion, this results in a level of residual risk that is inappropriate for the organization. Which of the following is the BEST course of action?",
    "options": [
      "Remove the disputed issue from the audit report.",
      "Discuss the matter with the chief risk officer (CRO).",
      "Discuss the matter with IS audit management and the chief audit executive (CAE).",
      "Note in the audit report that management accepts the risk and take no further action."
    ],
    "correct": "Discuss the matter with IS audit management and the chief audit executive (CAE)."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is an IS auditor's MOST important course of action to determine whether an organization's response to an incident was appropriate?",
    "options": [
      "Inspect the reporting sent to senior management following the incident.",
      "Review lessons learned to determine if correct actions have been taken",
      "Assess whether the organization contained the incident in a timely manner",
      "Assess whether the organization prioritized the incident based on policy."
    ],
    "correct": "Assess whether the organization prioritized the incident based on policy."
  },
  {
    "question": "As part of control self-assessment (CSA) activities in the finance department, an IS auditor identified that some of the controls were not tested and documented properly. Which of the following should the auditor do NEXT?",
    "options": [
      "Perform additional testing to complement CSA activities in the finance department.",
      "Expand the scope of the next internal audit planned for the finance department.",
      "Issue an audit report to the finance manager regarding the inadequate testing of controls.",
      "Provide guidance regarding control objectives to staff involved in the CSA."
    ],
    "correct": "Provide guidance regarding control objectives to staff involved in the CSA."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is an IS audit requirement when evaluating assertions made by management?",
    "options": [
      "To ensure all risks have been addressed",
      "To verify alignment with strategic goals",
      "To assess whether the assertions comply with the law",
      "To form conclusions about each assertion"
    ],
    "correct": "To form conclusions about each assertion"
  },
  {
    "question": "An audit has identified that business units have purchased cloud-based applications without IT's support. What is the GREATEST risk associated with this situation?",
    "options": [
      "The application purchases did not follow procurement policy.",
      "The application operating costs are not optimized",
      "The applications could be modified without advanced notice",
      "The applications may not reasonably protect data"
    ],
    "correct": "The applications may not reasonably protect data"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is accountable for an organization's enterprise risk management (ERM) program?",
    "options": [
      "Chief risk officer (CRO)",
      "Steering committee",
      "Executive management",
      "Board of directors"
    ],
    "correct": "Board of directors"
  },
  {
    "question": "Due to limited resources, two of an organization's developers also support production maintenance and change implementation. Which of the following is the IS auditor's BEST recommendation to address segregation of duties conflicts?",
    "options": [
      "Hire additional staff.",
      "Accept the risk",
      "Outsource change implementation.",
      "Implement a change monitoring process."
    ],
    "correct": "Implement a change monitoring process."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the BEST approach to minimize the risk of devices being unavailable following a required firmware upgrade?",
    "options": [
      "Deploy incrementally from a staging environment.",
      "Manually deploy to each device.",
      "Automatically deploy to all devices directly from the manufacturer.",
      "Roll into a mass distribution deployment."
    ],
    "correct": "Deploy incrementally from a staging environment."
  },
  {
    "question": "An IS auditor finds that an online retailer is experiencing unacceptable system response times due to high demand. Which of the following would BEST help to improve system performance?",
    "options": [
      "Establishing disk mirroring",
      "Optimizing data replication",
      "Implementing load balancing",
      "Changing firewall configuration"
    ],
    "correct": "Implementing load balancing"
  },
  {
    "question": "An employee approaches an IS auditor and expresses concern about a critical security issue in a newly installed application. Which of the following should the auditor do FIRST?",
    "options": [
      "Discuss the concern with audit management.",
      "Disclose the concern to legal counsel.",
      "Conduct a review of the application.",
      "Recommend reverting to the previous application."
    ],
    "correct": "Conduct a review of the application."
  },
  {
    "question": "For which of the following is the documentation of workaround processes critical to keeping business functions operational during recovery of IT systems?",
    "options": [
      "Threat and risk assessment",
      "Incident management process",
      "Business continuity plan (BCP)",
      "Business impact analysis (BIA)"
    ],
    "correct": "Incident management process"
  },
  {
    "question": "What should be an IS auditor's MOST important consideration when assessing whether an organization's IT project portfolio is appropriately prioritized?",
    "options": [
      "Business impact analysis (BIA)",
      "Cost-benefit analysis results",
      "The organization\\x92s business plan",
      "The organization's IT budget"
    ],
    "correct": "The organization\u0092s business plan"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is MOST important for an organization to include in a software escrow agreement when outsourcing software development to a third party?",
    "options": [
      "The escrow agent repository is to be securely protected against vendor access.",
      "The escrow agent repository is to be subject to periodic audits by the organization.",
      "The escrow agent repository is to be held in the organization's own country.",
      "The escrow agent repository is to be updated as the software product evolves."
    ],
    "correct": "The escrow agent repository is to be updated as the software product evolves."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the PRIMARY advantage of using an automated security log monitoring tool instead of conducting a manual review to monitor the use of privileged access?",
    "options": [
      "Reduced costs associated with automating the review",
      "Increased likelihood of detecting suspicious activity",
      "Ease of storing and maintaining log file",
      "Ease of log retrieval for audit purposes"
    ],
    "correct": "Increased likelihood of detecting suspicious activity"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which component of a business case provides the BEST indication that due diligence was performed during the vendor selection process?",
    "options": [
      "Problem statement",
      "Cost-benefit analysis",
      "Alternative solutions",
      "Management approval"
    ],
    "correct": "Alternative solutions"
  },
  {
    "question": "An IS auditor determines elevated administrator accounts for servers that are not properly checked out and then back in after each use. Which of the following is the MOST appropriate sampling technique to determine the scope of the problem?",
    "options": [
      "Statistical sampling",
      "Haphazard sampling",
      "Random sampling",
      "Stratified sampling"
    ],
    "correct": "Statistical sampling"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the BEST recommendation to drive accountability for achieving the desired outcomes specified in a benefits realization plan for an IT project?",
    "options": [
      "Ensure that the project manager has formal authority for managing the benefits realization plan.",
      "Assign responsibilities",
      "measures",
      "and timelines for each identified benefit within the plan.",
      "Document the dependencies between the project and other projects within the same program.",
      "Ensure that IT takes ownership for the delivery and tracking of all aspects of the benefits realization plan."
    ],
    "correct": "Assign responsibilities, measures, and timelines for each identified benefit within the plan."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following can increase the risk of data loss if data is corrupted or sabotaged?",
    "options": [
      "Unsecured backups",
      "Onsite backup storage",
      "Replication for backups",
      "Virtual backups"
    ],
    "correct": "Unsecured backups"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is MOST important for an IS auditor to verify when conducting a review of a potential third-party service provider?",
    "options": [
      "Whether a business impact analysis (BIA) has been completed",
      "Whether service level agreements (SLAs) are in place",
      "Whether required security controls have been established",
      "Whether a strategy for the use of third-party providers is established"
    ],
    "correct": "Whether required security controls have been established"
  },
  {
    "question": "A network analyst is monitoring the network after hours and detects activity that appears to be a brute-force attempt to compromise a critical server. After reviewing the alerts to ensure their accuracy, what should be done NEXT?",
    "options": [
      "Isolate the affected system.",
      "Perform a root cause analysis.",
      "Document all steps taken in a written report.",
      "Invoke the incident response plan"
    ],
    "correct": "Invoke the incident response plan"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following observations should be of GREATEST concern to an IS auditor assessing access controls for the accounts payable module of a ^finance system?",
    "options": [
      "Accounts payable staff have access to update vendor bank account details.",
      "Payment files are stored on a shared drive in a writable format prior to processing.",
      "Configured delegation limits do not align to the organization\\x92s delegations policy.",
      "The IS auditor was granted access to create purchase orders."
    ],
    "correct": "Accounts payable staff have access to update vendor bank account details."
  },
  {
    "question": "Emergency change control procedures MUST include which of the following requirements?",
    "options": [
      "Update production source libraries to reflect changes.",
      "Ensure audit logs track emergency changes.",
      "Request that the help desk make the changes.",
      "Use an emergency ID to move production programs into development."
    ],
    "correct": "Update production source libraries to reflect changes."
  },
  {
    "question": "The PRIMARY role of an IS auditor in the remediation of problems found during an audit engagement is to:",
    "options": [
      "present updated policies to management for approval.",
      "take ownership of the problems and oversee remediation efforts.",
      "explain the findings and provide general advice.",
      "help auditee management by providing the solution."
    ],
    "correct": "explain the findings and provide general advice."
  },
  {
    "question": "What would be an IS auditor's GREATEST concern when conducting an internal audit of a project to implement a customer relationship management (CRM) system?",
    "options": [
      "Additional budget required for project implementation",
      "Lack of stakeholder agreement on business requirements",
      "Lack of a post-implementation review",
      "Extended project scope beyond the design phase"
    ],
    "correct": "Lack of stakeholder agreement on business requirements"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the BEST way to ensure a vendor complies with system security requirements?",
    "options": [
      "Review past audits on the vendor's security compliance.",
      "Review past incidents reported by the vendor.",
      "Require a compliance clause in the vendor contract.",
      "Require security training for vendor staff."
    ],
    "correct": "Require a compliance clause in the vendor contract."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following should be the FIRST step for an IS audit manager who has been assigned to conduct a quality review on an audit that they supervised?",
    "options": [
      "Alert external auditors of the situation",
      "Notify senior audit leadership about the situation.",
      "Determine whether audit evidence supports audit conclusions.",
      "Discuss with the audit team to understand how conclusions were reached"
    ],
    "correct": "Determine whether audit evidence supports audit conclusions."
  },
  {
    "question": "Management has decided to accept a risk in response to a draft audit recommendation. Which of the following should be the IS auditor's NEXT course of action?",
    "options": [
      "Document management's acceptance in the audit report",
      "Ensure a follow-up audit is on next year\\x92s plan",
      "Escalate acceptance to the audit committee.",
      "Perform additional test procedures."
    ],
    "correct": "Document management's acceptance in the audit report"
  },
  {
    "question": "An IS auditor is reviewing a project that involves creating a secure mobile app for claims processing. As part of a security-in-development model for the program,threat modeling should begin during which project phase?",
    "options": [
      "Requirements definition",
      "Testing",
      "Architectural review",
      "Coding"
    ],
    "correct": "Requirements definition"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is MOST important to consider when assessing the scope of privacy concerns for an IT project?",
    "options": [
      "Data ownership",
      "End-user access rights",
      "Applicable laws and regulations",
      "Business requirements and data flows"
    ],
    "correct": "Applicable laws and regulations"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following would be of GREATEST concern to an |S auditor evaluating an organization's change management process?",
    "options": [
      "A list of authorized requestors for emergency changes does not exist.",
      "Change management meeting minutes are not available for several meetings.",
      "Change requests are not subject to prioritization.",
      "Changes are approved after being moved to production."
    ],
    "correct": "Changes are approved after being moved to production."
  },
  {
    "question": "An IS auditor has been asked to review the quality of data in a general ledger system. Which of the following would provide the auditor with the MOST meaningful results?",
    "options": [
      "Discussion of the largest account values with business owners",
      "Integrity checks against source documentation",
      "Interviews with system owners and operators",
      "System vulnerability assessment"
    ],
    "correct": "Integrity checks against source documentation"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following should be of GREATEST concern to an IS auditor when assessing the effectiveness of project risk management processes?",
    "options": [
      "The risk register is reviewed on a monthly basis.",
      "Some risks in the risk register were found to be rated incorrectly.",
      "The risk register is not maintained under version control.",
      "Risk owners have not been identified in the risk register."
    ],
    "correct": "Risk owners have not been identified in the risk register."
  },
  {
    "question": "During an audit of a mortgage processing application, an |S auditor identifies that the application allows all users to export large quantities of sensitive customer data. Which of the following is the BEST control for the auditor to recommend to mitigate this risk?",
    "options": [
      "Restrict download capability to authorized users.",
      "Mask sensitive data within the application.",
      "Require strong passwords for application login.",
      "Periodically recertify user access."
    ],
    "correct": "Periodically recertify user access."
  },
  {
    "question": "During a follow-up audit, an IS auditor learns that management has deferred the implementation of a previously agreed-upon recommendation. What is the responsibility of the auditor?",
    "options": [
      "Assess the impact of any risks the decision may pose to the organization.",
      "Obtain commitment from management to implement the recommendations.",
      "Report the decision to defer the implementation to the steering committee.",
      "Amend the final report to reflect the decision to defer the implementation."
    ],
    "correct": "Assess the impact of any risks the decision may pose to the organization."
  },
  {
    "question": "An IS auditor finds an emergency change request where an IT manager approved the change, modified the code on the production platform, and resolved the ticket. Which of the following should be the auditor's GREATEST concern?",
    "options": [
      "The IT manager performed the change.",
      "The change did not go through the change advisory board.",
      "There was no follow-up approval from the business.",
      "There was no user acceptance testing (UAT) prior to making the change."
    ],
    "correct": "There was no follow-up approval from the business."
  },
  {
    "question": "An IS auditor is tasked with reviewing an organization's purchase invoices to discover fictitious entries that may have been created as part of a suspected fraud scheme. Which of the following is the MOST effective data analysis technique for this situation?",
    "options": [
      "Benford's law",
      "Data mining",
      "Regression analysis",
      "Predictive analysis"
    ],
    "correct": "Predictive analysis"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following reliably associates users with their public keys and includes attributes that uniquely identify the users?",
    "options": [
      "Digital certificate",
      "Nonrepudiation",
      "Encryption",
      "Multi-factor authentication (MFA)"
    ],
    "correct": "Digital certificate"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following would an IS auditor find to be the GREATEST risk associated with the server room in a remote office location?",
    "options": [
      "The server room's location is known by people who work in the area.",
      "The server room does not have biometric controls.",
      "The server room does not have temperature controls.",
      "The server room is secured by a key lock instead of an electronic lock."
    ],
    "correct": "The server room does not have temperature controls."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following BEST enables an IS auditor to determine the effectiveness of controls for an audit area?",
    "options": [
      "SWOT analysis",
      "Control self-assessment (CSA)",
      "Prior audit results",
      "Control implementation methods"
    ],
    "correct": "Control implementation methods"
  },
  {
    "question": "The implementation of an IT governance framework requires that the board of directors of an organization:",
    "options": [
      "approves the IT strategy.",
      "addresses technical IT issues.",
      "has an IT strategy committee.",
      "approves all IT initiatives."
    ],
    "correct": "has an IT strategy committee."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the PRIMARY reason an IS auditor would recommend an automated management review process for network administration activity on a daily basis instead of quarterly?",
    "options": [
      "To detect network intrusions",
      "To identify system changes",
      "To identify failed login attempts",
      "To detect unauthorized transactions"
    ],
    "correct": "To detect unauthorized transactions"
  },
  {
    "question": "At the end of each business day. a business-critical application generates a report of financial transactions greater than a certain value, and an employee then checks these transactions for errors. What type of control is in place?",
    "options": [
      "Detective",
      "Preventive",
      "Deterrent",
      "Corrective"
    ],
    "correct": "Detective"
  },
  {
    "question": "An organization has implemented a policy to require minimum security control baselines when configuring servers or systems. What control type has been implemented? '",
    "options": [
      "Preventive",
      "Directive",
      "Compensating",
      "Corrective"
    ],
    "correct": "Directive"
  },
  {
    "question": "To ensure the effectiveness of project risk management, when should the project risk register be reviewed and updated?",
    "options": [
      "During the planning phase of the project",
      "At the end of each phase of the project ",
      "Throughout the lifetime of the project ",
      "During the design phase of the project"
    ],
    "correct": "Throughout the lifetime of the project"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is an effective way to ensure the integrity of file transfers in a peer-to-peer (P2P) computing environment?",
    "options": [
      "Associate a message authentication code with each file transferred",
      "Encrypt the packets shared between peers within the environment",
      "Connect the client computers in the environment to a jump server",
      "Ensure the files are transferred through an intrusion detection system (IDS)"
    ],
    "correct": "Associate a message authentication code with each file transferred"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the GREATEST impact as a result of the ongoing deterioration of a detective control?",
    "options": [
      "Decreased effectiveness of root cause analysis",
      "Decreased overall recovery time",
      "Increased number of false negatives in security logs",
      "Increased demand for storage space for logs"
    ],
    "correct": "Increased number of false negatives in security logs"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following controls BEST mitigates the risk associated with password compromise?",
    "options": [
      "Passwords are unique for each application",
      "Passwords have format restrictions.",
      "Passwords are stored in the cloud.",
      "Passwords are masked"
    ],
    "correct": "Passwords are unique for each application"
  },
  {
    "question": " During preparation for an IS audit of an organization's IT security processes, which of the following documents would BEST enable the IS auditor to understand the ownership of specific operational tasks?",
    "options": [
      "Documentation of non-functional requirements",
      "Security risk register",
      "RACI chart",
      "IT service delivery procedures"
    ],
    "correct": "RACI chart"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following findings is the GREATEST concern when reviewing a disaster recovery plan (DRP) with high availability requirements?",
    "options": [
      "Responsibilities are not defined for the recovery team.",
      "Annual tabletop testing is not required.",
      "Vendor contact information is not reviewed.",
      "Recovery time objectives (RTOs) are not defined."
    ],
    "correct": "Recovery time objectives (RTOs) are not defined."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following BEST indicates a need to review an organization s information security policy?",
    "options": [
      "Increasing complexity of business transactions",
      "Increasing exceptions approved by management",
      "High number of low-risk findings in the audit report",
      "Completion of annual IT risk assessment"
    ],
    "correct": "Increasing exceptions approved by management"
  },
  {
    "question": "The waterfall life cycle model of software development is BEST suited for which of the following situations?",
    "options": [
      "The project will involve the use of new technology.",
      "The project is subject to time pressures",
      "The project requirements are well understood",
      "The project intends to apply an object-oriented design approach"
    ],
    "correct": "The project requirements are well understood"
  },
  {
    "question": "When evaluating the design of controls related to network monitoring, which of the following is MOST important for an is auditor to review?",
    "options": [
      "Network topology diagrams",
      "The ISP service level agreement (SLA)",
      "Incident monitoring logs",
      "Reports of network traffic analysis"
    ],
    "correct": "Network topology diagrams"
  },
  {
    "question": "While reviewing the effectiveness of an incident response program, an IS auditor notices a high number of reported incidents involving malware originating from removable media found by employees. Which of the following is the MOST appropriate recommendation to management?",
    "options": [
      "Install an additional antivirus program to increase protection.",
      "Ensure the antivirus program contains up-to-date signature files for all company devices.",
      "Implement an organization-wide removable media policy.",
      "Restrict access to removable media ports on company devices."
    ],
    "correct": "Implement an organization-wide removable media policy."
  },
  {
    "question": "An auditee has not implemented an internal IS auditor's recommended remediation actions, citing cost and capacity constraints. Which of the following would be the BEST course of action for the auditor?",
    "options": [
      "Work with the auditee to develop a mitigation plan.",
      "Invite an independent third party to review the recommendations.",
      "Provide industry documentation supporting the recommendations.",
      "Escalate to the audit committee."
    ],
    "correct": "Work with the auditee to develop a mitigation plan."
  },
  {
    "question": "An IS auditor is reviewing documentation from a change that was applied to an application. Which of the following findings would be the GREATEST concern?",
    "options": [
      "Testing documentation is kept in hard copy format.",
      "Testing documentation does not show manager approval.",
      "Testing documentation is approved prior to completion of user acceptance testing (UAT).",
      "Testing documentation is dated three weeks before the system implementation date."
    ],
    "correct": "Testing documentation is approved prior to completion of user acceptance testing (UAT)."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following would BEST reduce the operational risks associated with the potential for a third-party software vendor to go out of business?",
    "options": [
      "Vendor software support agreements",
      "Evidence of the vendor's financial stability",
      "Software escrow agreements",
      "Service level agreements (SLAs) in the contract"
    ],
    "correct": "Software escrow agreements"
  },
  {
    "question": "An IS auditor observes that an organization's IT service desk is closing tickets before problems are fully resolved, causing them to be reopened and impacting service levels. Which of the following is the BEST recommendation to address this situation?",
    "options": [
      "Develop training on service desk ticket management.",
      "Review the accuracy of date and time stamps on tickets.",
      "Ensure updates to tickets are traceable to service desk staff",
      "Extend the mean time to resolve problem tickets."
    ],
    "correct": "Ensure updates to tickets are traceable to service desk staff"
  },
  {
    "question": "An organization has both an IT strategy committee and an IT steering committee When reviewing the minutes of the IT steering committee an IS auditor would expect to find that the committee",
    "options": [
      "acquired and assigned appropriate resources for projects",
      "assessed the contribution of IT to the business",
      "compared the risk and return of IT investments",
      "reviewed the achievement of the strategic IT objective"
    ],
    "correct": "acquired and assigned appropriate resources for projects"
  },
  {
    "question": "The PRIMARY purpose for establishing checkpoints in information processing systems is to provide for:",
    "options": [
      "periodic balancing of processing results during system execution.",
      "monitoring system performance against preestablished specifications",
      "restart of processing after system failure without having to start from the beginning.",
      "reentry of corrected transactions rejected in previous processing phases."
    ],
    "correct": "restart of processing after system failure without having to start from the beginning."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is an analytical review procedure for a payroll system?",
    "options": [
      "Performing reasonableness tests by multiplying the number of employees by the average wage rate",
      "Testing hours reported on time sheets",
      "Performing penetration attempts on the payroll system",
      "Evaluating the performance of the payroll system using benchmarking software"
    ],
    "correct": "Performing reasonableness tests by multiplying the number of employees by the average wage rate"
  },
  {
    "question": "A security review focused on data loss prevention (DLP) revealed the organization has no visibility to data stored in the cloud. What is the IS auditor's BEST recommendation to address this issue?",
    "options": [
      "Utilize a DLP tool on desktops to monitor user activities.",
      "Enhance the firewall at the network perimeter",
      "Implement a file system scanner to discover data stared in the cloud",
      "Employ a cloud access security broker (CASB)."
    ],
    "correct": "Employ a cloud access security broker (CASB)."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is MOST important when implementing a data classification program?",
    "options": [
      "Formalizing data ownership",
      "Planning for secure storage capacity",
      "Developing a privacy policy",
      "Understanding the data classification levels"
    ],
    "correct": "Formalizing data ownership"
  },
  {
    "question": "An organization is planning an acquisition and has engaged an IS auditor to evaluate the IT governance framework of the target company. Which of the following would be MOST helpful in determining the effectiveness of the framework?",
    "options": [
      "Recent third-party IS audit reports",
      "Current and previous internal IS audit reports",
      "Self-assessment reports of IT capability and maturity",
      "IT performance benchmarking reports with competitors"
    ],
    "correct": "Recent third-party IS audit reports"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following should be the GREATEST concern to an IS auditor reviewing an organization s job scheduling practices?",
    "options": [
      "Job processing procedures are missing",
      "Jobs are executed during working hours,",
      "Job dependencies are undefined",
      "Most jobs are run manually"
    ],
    "correct": "Job dependencies are undefined"
  },
  {
    "question": "An IS auditor finds that the cost of developing an application is now projected to significantly exceed the budget Which of the following is the GREATEST risk to communicate to senior management?",
    "options": [
      "Increased staff turnover",
      "Project abandonment",
      "Inability to achieve expected benefits",
      "Noncompliance with project methodology"
    ],
    "correct": "Inability to achieve expected benefits"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the BEST way to determine the effectiveness of an organization s current patch management system?",
    "options": [
      "Perform a vulnerability assessment",
      "Perform secure code review",
      "Perform a network scan",
      "Perform penetration testing"
    ],
    "correct": "Perform a vulnerability assessment"
  },
  {
    "question": "An organization has engaged a third party to implement an application to perform business-critical calculations Which of the following is the MOST important process to help ensure the application provides accurate calculations?",
    "options": [
      "Quality assurance (QA)",
      "Key performance indicator (KPl) monitoring",
      "Change management",
      "Configuration management"
    ],
    "correct": "Change management"
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of a checksum on an amount Field in an electronic data interchange (EDI) communication of financial transactions is to ensure",
    "options": [
      "Authorization.",
      "Integrity",
      "Non-repudiation",
      "Authenticity"
    ],
    "correct": "Integrity"
  },
  {
    "question": "An IS auditor reviewing the system development life cycle (SDLC) finds there is no requirement for business cases Which of the following should be of GREATEST concern to the organization?",
    "options": [
      "Business resources have not been optimally assigned.",
      "Business impacts of projects are not adequately analyzed",
      "Vendor selection criteria are not sufficiently evaluated",
      "Project costs exceed established budgets."
    ],
    "correct": "Business impacts of projects are not adequately analyzed"
  },
  {
    "question": "Management has requested a post-implementation review of a newly Implemented purchasing package to determine the extent that business requirements are being met. Which of the following is MOST likely to be assessed?",
    "options": [
      "Results of live processing",
      "Acceptance testing results",
      "Implementation methodology",
      "Purchasing guidelines and policies"
    ],
    "correct": "Results of live processing"
  },
  {
    "question": "Following an application update, an IS auditor has identified performance degradation potentially resulting from a code defect. What type of testing is the BEST way to help prevent this issue in the future'?",
    "options": [
      "Regression testing",
      "Capacity testing",
      "Resiliency testing",
      "Performance testing"
    ],
    "correct": "Regression testing"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is acceptable to be left out of a final audit report?",
    "options": [
      "Findings of minimal risk to the overall organization",
      "The cause and risk associated with a reported issue",
      "The nature and extent of audit procedures conducted",
      "Significant findings previously communicated to management"
    ],
    "correct": "Findings of minimal risk to the overall organization"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is MOST helpful to a project manager in mitigating risk associated with frequent changes in project requirements",
    "options": [
      "Performing mid-term project reviews",
      "Monitoring changes in risk factors",
      "Implementing formal reviews of changes",
      "Conducting post-implementation reviews"
    ],
    "correct": "Implementing formal reviews of changes"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following constitutes an effective detective control in a distributed processing environment-?",
    "options": [
      "A log of privileged account use is reviewed",
      "User IDs are suspended after three incorrect passwords have been entered",
      "Users are required to request additional access via an electronic mail system",
      "A disaster recovery plan (DRP) is in place for the entire system"
    ],
    "correct": "A log of privileged account use is reviewed"
  },
  {
    "question": "When an intrusion into an organizations network is detected, which of the following should be done FIRST?",
    "options": [
      "Notify senior management",
      "Block all compromised network nodes",
      "Identify nodes that have been compromised",
      "Contact law enforcement"
    ],
    "correct": "Identify nodes that have been compromised"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following management decisions presents the GREATEST risk associated with data leakage?",
    "options": [
      "There is no requirement for desktops to be encrypted",
      "Staff are allowed to work remotely",
      "Security policies have not been updated in the past year",
      "Security awareness training is not provided to staff"
    ],
    "correct": "Security awareness training is not provided to staff"
  },
  {
    "question": "In order to be useful a key performance indicator (KPI) MUST",
    "options": [
      "be measurable in percentages",
      "be changed frequently to reflect organizational strategy",
      "be approved by management",
      "have a target value"
    ],
    "correct": "have a target value"
  },
  {
    "question": "A senior IS auditor suspects that a PC may have been used to perpetrate fraud in a finance department. The auditor should FIRST report this suspicion to:",
    "options": [
      "the police.",
      "auditee line management",
      "the audit committee.",
      "audit management."
    ],
    "correct": "audit management."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the MOST important objective of a vendor selection review?",
    "options": [
      "To ensure the vendor's security policies have been audited",
      "To ensure the vendor proposal fulfills the business requirements",
      "To ensure the vendor's data center is located in the same legal jurisdiction",
      "To ensure the vendor source code library will be provided"
    ],
    "correct": "To ensure the vendor proposal fulfills the business requirements"
  },
  {
    "question": "An IS auditor finds that communication closets requiring electronic swipe card access are missing access logs. Which of the following should be done NEXT?",
    "options": [
      "Determine whether any access swipe cards have been lost or stolen.",
      "Determine whether anything is missing from the closets.",
      "Determine whether management approved the access policy.",
      "Determine whether there are video cameras covering the entrances."
    ],
    "correct": "Determine whether there are video cameras covering the entrances."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following provides the BEST estimate of the complexity associated with a software development project for a web-based application?",
    "options": [
      "Function point analysis",
      "Lines of code",
      "Value adjustment factor",
      "Constructive cost model"
    ],
    "correct": "Function point analysis"
  },
  {
    "question": "During a pre-implementation review, an IS auditor notes that some scenarios have not been tested. Management has indicated that the project is critical and cannot be postponed. Which of the following is the auditor's BEST course of action?",
    "options": [
      "Help management complete remaining scenario testing before implementation.",
      "Determine whether the tested scenarios covered the most significant project risks.",
      "Perform remaining scenario testing in the production environment post implementation.",
      "Recommend project implementation be postponed until all scenarios have been tested."
    ],
    "correct": "Determine whether the tested scenarios covered the most significant project risks."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following should be done FIRST when creating a data protection program?",
    "options": [
      "Deploy intrusion detection systems (IDS).",
      "Implement data loss prevention (DLP) controls.",
      "Perform classification based on standards.",
      "Test logical access controls for effectiveness."
    ],
    "correct": "Perform classification based on standards."
  },
  {
    "question": "During the audit of an enterprise resource planning (ERP) system, an IS auditor found an application patch was applied to the production environment It is MOST important for the IS auditor to verify approval from the:",
    "options": [
      "information security officer",
      "system administrator.",
      "information asset owner.",
      "project manager"
    ],
    "correct": "information asset owner."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following should be verified FIRST when reviewing the implementation of a data classification policy?",
    "options": [
      "Database integrity checks have been completed.",
      "A data backup policy is established.",
      "Data owners are identified."
    ],
    "correct": "Data owners are identified."
  },
  {
    "question": "A risk assessment has been completed.",
    "options": [
      "A business area received an audit finding because an administrator made unapproved emergency changes to a critical system. Which of the following would BEST prevent unapproved changes in the future?",
      "Dual-control temporary emergency access accounts",
      "Updated emergency change management procedures",
      "Two-factor authentication on emergency access accounts",
      "Regular emergency change-control log reviews"
    ],
    "correct": "Dual-control temporary emergency access accounts"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following provides an organization with the fastest resumption of processing following a disk failure?",
    "options": [
      "Warm site recovery",
      "Mirroring",
      "Direct backup to server",
      "Batch replication"
    ],
    "correct": "Mirroring"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the BEST way to reduce the chance of false positive alerts in an intrusion prevention system (IPS) from interrupting network communications?",
    "options": [
      "Conduct periodic IPS performance fine-tuning.",
      "Complement IPS return signals with firewall alerts.",
      "Classify alerts from the IPS by event category.",
      "Shift the architecture to a host-based IPS configuration"
    ],
    "correct": "Classify alerts from the IPS by event category."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following BEST reduces the risk of a network transmission failure?",
    "options": [
      "Alternative or diverse routing",
      "Server load balancing",
      "Compression software to minimize transmission duration",
      "A packet filtering firewall to reroute messages"
    ],
    "correct": "Alternative or diverse routing"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following findings would be of GREATEST concern when evaluating an organization's endpoint computer patch management process?",
    "options": [
      "Rollbacks were required for some patches.",
      "Patching is performed every three months.",
      "Patching is performed manually for some systems.",
      "Patch implementation took longer than expected."
    ],
    "correct": "Patching is performed every three months."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the GREATEST benefit of incorporating data analytics in internal audit engagements?",
    "options": [
      "Sampling efficiencies",
      "Easier data classification and stratification",
      "Enhanced understanding of sample populations",
      "Improved substantive analysis"
    ],
    "correct": "Improved substantive analysis"
  },
  {
    "question": "At which stage of the system development life cycle (SDLC) is it MOST beneficial to perform a risk assessment?",
    "options": [
      "Prior to system development",
      "During business case development",
      "At each stage of the life cycle",
      "Prior to system deployment"
    ],
    "correct": "At each stage of the life cycle"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is MOST important to consider when selecting an automated fire suppression system for an unmanned data center?",
    "options": [
      "Likelihood of fires at the data center",
      "Maintenance costs",
      "Onsite support by the vendor",
      "Potential damage to equipment"
    ],
    "correct": "Potential damage to equipment"
  },
  {
    "question": "An IS auditor learns that a business owner violated the organization s security policy by creating a web page with access to production data The auditor's NEXT step should be to",
    "options": [
      "escalate to senior management",
      "shut down the web page",
      "assess the sensitivity of the production data ",
      "determine if sufficient access controls exist"
    ],
    "correct": "assess the sensitivity of the production data"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following roles is PRIMARILY responsible for mitigating the risk of benefits not being realized in an IT project?",
    "options": [
      "Project sponsor",
      "Chief risk officer (CRO)",
      "Quality assurance (QA) manager",
      "Project manager"
    ],
    "correct": "Project sponsor"
  },
  {
    "question": "When performing an audit of a third-party provider, it is MOST important to ensure:",
    "options": [
      "a vendor monitoring process has been implemented.",
      "the service level agreement (SLA) is monitored.",
      "a vendor relationship manager is assigned.",
      "items identified in the risk assessment have been addressed."
    ],
    "correct": "items identified in the risk assessment have been addressed."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following would be MOST useful to an IS auditor when making recommendations to enable continual improvement of IT processes over time?",
    "options": [
      "Benchmarking studies",
      "IT incident log",
      "IT risk register",
      "Maturity model"
    ],
    "correct": "Maturity model"
  },
  {
    "question": "In response to a finding that several vendor-supplied security fixes had not been applied to a business-critical application management has agreed to apply all the security patches During follow-up procedures which of the following is MOST important for the auditor to verify?",
    "options": [
      "Parallel testing has been performed",
      "Code compression testing has been performed",
      "Progression testing has been performed",
      "Regression testing has been performed"
    ],
    "correct": "Regression testing has been performed"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is MOST important for an IS auditor to identify in a project business case?",
    "options": [
      "A comprehensive listing of business requirements",
      "An assessment of expected benefits versus projected cost",
      "Security controls to be implemented during the project",
      "Selection criteria for vendors involved in the project"
    ],
    "correct": "A comprehensive listing of business requirements"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following components of a risk assessment is MOST helpful to management in determining the level of risk mitigation to apply?",
    "options": [
      "Risk classification",
      "Impact assessment",
      "Control self-assessment (CSA)",
      "Risk identification"
    ],
    "correct": "Impact assessment"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following provides the BEST assurance that vendor-supported software remains up to date?",
    "options": [
      "Version management",
      "Software asset management",
      "Licensing agreement and escrow",
      "Release and patch management"
    ],
    "correct": "Version management"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following should an IS auditor recommend as a PRIMARY area of focus when an organization decides to outsource technical support for its external customers?",
    "options": [
      "Ensure right to audit is included within the contract.",
      "Monitor customer satisfaction with the change.",
      "Minimize costs related to the third-party agreement",
      "Align service level agreements (SLAs) with current needs."
    ],
    "correct": "Align service level agreements (SLAs) with current needs."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following should an |S auditor do FIRST when determining whether unauthorized changes have been made to production code?",
    "options": [
      "Examine the change control system records and trace them forward to object code files.",
      "Review change-approved designations established within the change control system",
      "Review access control permissions operating within the production program libraries.",
      "Examine object code to find instances of changes and trace them back to change control records."
    ],
    "correct": "Examine object code to find instances of changes and trace them back to change control records."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the PRIMARY benefit of effective implementation of appropriate data classification?",
    "options": [
      "Ability to meet business requirements",
      "Assurance that sensitive data is encrypted",
      "Management of business risk to sensitive data",
      "Increased accuracy of sensitive data"
    ],
    "correct": "Management of business risk to sensitive data"
  },
  {
    "question": "The PRIMARY reason to assign data ownership for protection of data is to establish",
    "options": [
      "reliability",
      "accountability",
      "traceability",
      "authority"
    ],
    "correct": "accountability"
  },
  {
    "question": "An incident response team has been notified of a virus outbreak in a network subnet. Which of the following should be the NEXT step?",
    "options": [
      "Remove and restore the affected systems.",
      "Focus on limiting the damage.",
      "Verify that the compromised systems are fully functional.",
      "Document the incident."
    ],
    "correct": "Focus on limiting the damage."
  },
  {
    "question": "An IS auditor observes an undocumented open port within the corporate firewall that is in conflict with the baseline firewall configuration. Which of the following is the BES^ recommendation to prevent recurrence?",
    "options": [
      "Deploy updated patches.",
      "Perform a risk assessment.",
      "Follow change management",
      "Initiate incident response."
    ],
    "correct": "Follow change management"
  },
  {
    "question": "IT management has accepted the risk associated with an IS auditor's finding due to the cost and complexity of the corrective actions. Which of the following should be the auditor's NEXT course of action?",
    "options": [
      "Notify senior management.",
      "Perform a cost-benefit analysis",
      "Document and inform the audit committee",
      "Report the finding to external regulators."
    ],
    "correct": "Document and inform the audit committee"
  },
  {
    "question": "During an annual payroll audit, an IS auditor identifies issues that were also in the previous year's audit. Which of the following is the GREATEST concern?",
    "options": [
      "The management action plan for the issue was extended.",
      "Management has accepted the risk for this issue.",
      "The client implemented alternative controls.",
      "The client does not understand the issue."
    ],
    "correct": "Management has accepted the risk for this issue."
  },
  {
    "question": "Following an IT audit, management has decided to accept the risk highlighted in the audit report Which of the following would provide the MOST assurance to the IS auditor that management is adequately balancing the needs of the business with the need to manage risk?",
    "options": [
      "Identified risk is reported into the organization\\x92s risk committee",
      "Potential impact and likelihood are adequately documented",
      "Established criteria exist for accepting and approving risk",
      "A communication plan exists for informing parties impacted by the risk"
    ],
    "correct": "Established criteria exist for accepting and approving risk"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the PRIMARY objective of enterprise architecture (EA)?",
    "options": [
      "Maintaining detailed system documentation",
      "Enforcing the IT policy across the organization",
      "Executing customized development and delivery of projects",
      "Managing and planning for IT investments"
    ],
    "correct": "Maintaining detailed system documentation"
  },
  {
    "question": "An IS auditor reviewing an information processing environment decides to conduct external penetration testing Which of the following Is MOST appropriate to include in the audit scope for the organization to distinguish between the auditor's penetration attacks and actual attacks?",
    "options": [
      "Testing techniques of simulated attacks",
      "Source IP addresses of simulated attacks",
      "Timing of simulated attacks",
      "Restricted host IP addresses of simulated attacks"
    ],
    "correct": "Source IP addresses of simulated attacks"
  },
  {
    "question": "An IS auditor is evaluating the log management system for an organization with devices and systems in multiple geographic locations. Which of the following is MOST important for the auditor to verify?",
    "options": [
      "Log files of the servers are synchronized.",
      "Log files are concurrently updated.",
      "Log files are encrypted and digitally signed.",
      "Log files are reviewed in multiple locations."
    ],
    "correct": "Log files of the servers are synchronized."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the MOST appropriate control to ensure the identity of an email sender?",
    "options": [
      "Digital signature",
      "Automatic return receipt",
      "Multi-factor authentication (MFA)",
      "Transport Layer Security (TLS)"
    ],
    "correct": "Digital signature"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the GREATEST concern related to an organization\u0092s data classification processes?",
    "options": [
      "The data classification processes are not aligned with industry standards",
      "Systems used to manage the data classification processes are not synchronized",
      "Users responsible for managing records are unaware of the data classification processes",
      "The data classification processes have not been updated in the last year"
    ],
    "correct": "Users responsible for managing records are unaware of the data classification processes"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the GREATEST risk if two users have concurrent access io the same database record?",
    "options": [
      "Referential integrity",
      "Entity integrity",
      "Availability integrity",
      "Data integrity"
    ],
    "correct": "Data integrity"
  },
  {
    "question": "If a recent release of a program has to be backed out of production, the corresponding changes within the delta version of the code should be:",
    "options": [
      "reinstalled when replacing the version back into production.",
      "filed in production for future reference in researching the problem.",
      "applied to the source code that reflects the version in production",
      "eliminated from the source code that reflects the version in production."
    ],
    "correct": "applied to the source code that reflects the version in production"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the MOST significant risk when an application uses individual end-user accounts to access the underlying database?",
    "options": [
      "Application may not capture a complete audit trail.",
      "User accounts may remain active after a termination.",
      "Multiple connects to the database are used and slow the process.",
      "Users may be able to circumvent application controls."
    ],
    "correct": "Users may be able to circumvent application controls."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following backup types BEST enables an organization to recover data following a ransomware attack?",
    "options": [
      "Offline backup",
      "Online data synchronization",
      "Incremental backup",
      "Differential backup"
    ],
    "correct": "Offline backup"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which type of control has been established when an organization implements a security information and event management (SIEM) system?",
    "options": [
      "Preventive",
      "Corrective",
      "Detective",
      "Directive"
    ],
    "correct": "Detective"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which off the following attack types is MOST effectively addressed by an organization's security awareness program?",
    "options": [
      "Structured query language (SQL) injection",
      "Distributed denial of service (DDoS)",
      "Man-in-the-middle",
      "Phishing"
    ],
    "correct": "Phishing"
  },
  {
    "question": "An audit identified that a computer system is not assigning sequential purchase order numbers to order requests The IS auditor is conducting an audit follow-up to determine if management has resolved this finding. Which of the following is the MOST reliable follow-up procedure?",
    "options": [
      "Review the documentation of recent changes to implement sequential order numbering",
      "Inspect the system settings and transaction logs to determine if sequential order numbers are generated",
      "Examine a sample of system generated purchase orders obtained from management",
      "Inquire with management if the system has been configured and tested to generate sequential order numbers"
    ],
    "correct": "Inspect the system settings and transaction logs to determine if sequential order numbers are generated"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following security measures will reduce the risk of propagation when a cyberattack occurs?",
    "options": [
      "Network segmentation",
      "Perimeter firewall",
      "Data loss prevention (DLP) system",
      "Web application firewall (WAF)"
    ],
    "correct": "Network segmentation"
  },
  {
    "question": "An IS auditor is reviewing processes for importing market price data from external data providers Which of the following findings should the auditor consider MOST critical?",
    "options": [
      "The transfer protocol is not encrypted.",
      "The transfer protocol does not require authentication,",
      "The quality of the data is not monitored.",
      "Imported data is not disposed of frequently"
    ],
    "correct": "The quality of the data is not monitored."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following would MOST effectively ensure the integrity of data transmitted over a network?",
    "options": [
      "Message encryption",
      "Certificate authority (CA)",
      "C Steganography",
      "Message digest"
    ],
    "correct": "Message digest"
  },
  {
    "question": "Data from a system of sensors located outside of a network is received by the open ports on a server Which of the following is the BEST way to ensure the integrity of the data being collected from the sensor system?",
    "options": [
      "Implement network address translation on the sensor system.",
      "Transmit the sensor data via a virtual private network (VPN) to the server",
      "Route the traffic from the sensor system through a proxy server",
      "Hash the data that is transmitted from the sensor system"
    ],
    "correct": "Hash the data that is transmitted from the sensor system"
  },
  {
    "question": "A steering committee established to oversee an organization's digital transformation program is MOST likely to be involved with which of the following activities?",
    "options": [
      "Documenting requirements ",
      "Designing interface controls ",
      "Preparing project status reports",
      "Reviewing escalated project issues"
    ],
    "correct": "Reviewing escalated project issues"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which type of risk would MOST influence the selection of a sampling methodology?",
    "options": [
      "Inherent ",
      "Residual",
      "Detection ",
      "Control"
    ],
    "correct": "Detection"
  },
  {
    "question": "During the implementation of an enterprise resource planning (ERP) system, an IS auditor is reviewing the results of user acceptance testing (UAT). Which of the following should be the auditor's PRIMARY focus?",
    "options": [
      "Determine if application interfaces have been satisfactorily tested.",
      "Verify that system integration testing was performed.",
      "Determine if the business process owner has signed off on the results.",
      "Confirm that all errors have been communicated to end users."
    ],
    "correct": "Determine if the business process owner has signed off on the results."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which type of testing is BEST for evaluating how well an application functions with other IT systems?",
    "options": [
      "Final acceptance testing",
      "Unit testing",
      "System testing",
      "Integration testing"
    ],
    "correct": "Integration testing"
  },
  {
    "question": "A firewall has been installed on the company\u0092s web server Which concern does the firewall address'?",
    "options": [
      "Accessing information by the outside world",
      "Availability of the information",
      "Connectivity to the Internet",
      "Unauthorized modification of information by internal users"
    ],
    "correct": "Accessing information by the outside world"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of fine following is an IS auditor's BEST recommendation to mitigate the risk of eavesdropping associated with an application programming interface (API) integration implementation?",
    "options": [
      "Mask the API endpoints",
      "Implement Simple Object Access Protocol (SOAP)",
      "Encrypt the extensible markup language (XML) file",
      "Implement Transport Layer Security (TLS)"
    ],
    "correct": "Implement Transport Layer Security (TLS)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following would BEST help to ensure that potential security issues are considered by the development team as part of incremental changes to Agile-developed software?",
    "options": [
      "Include a mandatory step to analyze the security impact when making changes",
      "Assign the security risk analysis to a specially trained member of the project management office",
      "Deploy changes in a controlled environment and observe for security defects",
      "Mandate that the change analyses are documented in a standard format"
    ],
    "correct": "Include a mandatory step to analyze the security impact when making changes"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following observations regarding change management should be considered the MOST serious risk by an IS auditor?",
    "options": [
      "The change is deployed two weeks after approval.",
      "The change is not approved by the business owners.",
      "The development of the change is not cost effective",
      "There is no software used to track change management."
    ],
    "correct": "The change is not approved by the business owners."
  },
  {
    "question": "An IS auditor is reviewing a network diagram. Which of the following would be the BEST llocation for placement of a firewall?",
    "options": [
      "At borders of network segments with different security levels",
      "Between virtual focal area networks- (VLANs)",
      "Between each host and the local network switch/hub",
      "Inside the demilitarized zone (DMZ)"
    ],
    "correct": "At borders of network segments with different security levels"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of fine following provides the MOST useful information regarding an organization's risk appetite and tolerance",
    "options": [
      "Gap analysis",
      "Audit reports",
      "Risk register",
      "Risk profile"
    ],
    "correct": "Gap analysis"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following should an IS auditor be MOST concerned with when a system uses RFID?",
    "options": [
      "Scalability",
      "Nonrepudiation",
      "Maintainability",
      "Privacy"
    ],
    "correct": "Privacy"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the BEST disposal method for flash drives that previously stored confidential data?",
    "options": [
      "Degaussing",
      "Destruction",
      "Cryptographic erasure",
      "Overwriting"
    ],
    "correct": "Degaussing"
  },
  {
    "question": "When planning a review of IT governance, an IS auditor is MOST likely to",
    "options": [
      "define key performance indicators (KPIs)",
      "examine audit committee minutes for IT-related controls",
      "assess whether business process owner responsibilities are consistent",
      "obtain information about the control framework adopted by management"
    ],
    "correct": "obtain information about the control framework adopted by management"
  },
  {
    "question": "An organization recently switched vendors for its hardware service and maintenance. The new contract specifies a longer response time than the organization's requirements. Which of the following is the GREATEST risk of this change?",
    "options": [
      "Disaster recovery plans (DRPs) may have increased dependence on the new vendor.",
      "Unexpected downtime may impact key business processes.",
      "There may be an increase in shadow IT occurrences.",
      "Business data may not be destroyed properly after the retention period."
    ],
    "correct": "Unexpected downtime may impact key business processes."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following should be the GREATEST concern for an IS auditor performing a post-implementation review for a major system upgrade?",
    "options": [
      "Changes are promoted to production by the development group.",
      "Object code can be accessed by the development group.",
      "Developers have access to the testing environment.",
      "Change approvals are not formally documented."
    ],
    "correct": "Object code can be accessed by the development group."
  },
  {
    "question": "Management is concerned about sensitive information being intentionally or unintentionally emailed as attachments outside the organization by employees What is the MOST important task before implementing any associated email controls?",
    "options": [
      "Develop an acceptable use policy for end-user computing (EUC)",
      "Provide notification to employees about possible email monitoring",
      "Require al! employees to sign nondisclosure agreements (NDAs)",
      "Develop an information classification scheme"
    ],
    "correct": "Develop an information classification scheme"
  },
  {
    "question": "An organization produces control reports with a desktop application that accesses data in the central production database Which of the following would give an IS auditor concern about the reliability of these reports?",
    "options": [
      "The reports are available to all end users.",
      "The reports are printed by the same person who reviews them",
      "The report definitions can be modified by end users.",
      "The report definitions file is not included in routine backups"
    ],
    "correct": "The report definitions can be modified by end users."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following metrics would BEST indicate compliance with a policy that requires all new employees to receive security awareness training?",
    "options": [
      "Percentage of new hires who report incidents",
      "Percentage of new hires that have completed the training",
      "Number of terminations for policy violations",
      "Average security awareness training scores"
    ],
    "correct": "Percentage of new hires that have completed the training"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following BEST enables an IS auditor to confirm the batch processing to post transactions from an input source is successful?",
    "options": [
      "Aggregate monetary amount",
      "Error log review",
      "Total number of items",
      "Hash totals"
    ],
    "correct": "Total number of items"
  },
  {
    "question": "An external attacker spoofing an internal Internet Protocol (IP) address can BEST be detected by which of the following?",
    "options": [
      "Using a state table to compare the message states of each packet as it enters the system",
      "Using static IP addresses for identification",
      "Comparing the source address to the domain name server (DNS) entry",
      "Comparing the source address to the interface used as the entry point"
    ],
    "correct": "Comparing the source address to the domain name server (DNS) entry"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which of the following situations is it MOST appropriate to implement data mirroring as part of a recovery strategy?",
    "options": [
      "When the recovery point objective (RPO) is short",
      "When the risk of a ransomware attack is high",
      "When disaster tolerance is low",
      "When the mean time between failures (MTBF) is long"
    ],
    "correct": "When disaster tolerance is low"
  },
  {
    "question": "When is the MOST appropriate time to establish metrics for assessing the effectiveness of an outsourced IT project?",
    "options": [
      "During the configuration phase",
      "During the acquisition phase",
      "During the initiation phase",
      "During the testing phase"
    ],
    "correct": "During the initiation phase"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the BEST audit procedure to determine whether a firewall is configured in compliance with the organization's security policy?",
    "options": [
      "Reviewing the system log",
      "Reviewing the parameter settings",
      "Performing a vulnerability assessment",
      "Conducting penetration testing"
    ],
    "correct": "Reviewing the parameter settings"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following BEST addresses the availability of an online store?",
    "options": [
      "RAID level 5 storage devices",
      "A mirrored site at another location",
      "Clustered architecture",
      "Online backups"
    ],
    "correct": "Clustered architecture"
  },
  {
    "question": "An organization is ready to implement a new IT solution consisting of multiple modules The last module updates the processed data into the database Which of the following findings should be of MOST concern to the IS auditor?",
    "options": [
      "Lack of a data dictionary",
      "Absence of a formal change approval process",
      "Use of weak encryption",
      "Lack of input validation"
    ],
    "correct": "Lack of input validation"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is MOST important for an IS auditor to review when evaluating a project investment decision-making process?",
    "options": [
      "Business risk assessment",
      "Project budget",
      "Business impact analysis (BIA)",
      "Cost-benefit analysis"
    ],
    "correct": "Cost-benefit analysis"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following data provides the MOST useful input when performing a business impact analysis (BIA)?",
    "options": [
      "Projected cost of goods sold",
      "Expected costs for recovering the business",
      "Cost-benefit analysis of running the current business",
      "Cost of regulatory compliance"
    ],
    "correct": "Expected costs for recovering the business"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following should be of GREATEST concern to an IS auditor reviewing an organization's IT process performance reports over the last quarter?",
    "options": [
      "Metrics are not aligned with industry benchmarks.",
      "Performance reporting includes too many technical terms.",
      "Key performance indicators (KPIs) were met in only one month.",
      "Metrics were defined without stakeholder review."
    ],
    "correct": "Metrics were defined without stakeholder review."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the MOST important privacy consideration for an organization that uses a cloud service provider to process customer data?",
    "options": [
      "Customer data transferred to the service provider must be reported to the regulatory authority.",
      "Data privacy must be managed in accordance with the regulations applicable Io the organization.",
      "Data privacy must be monitored in accordance with industry standards and best practices.",
      "No personal information may be transferred to the service provider without notifying the customer."
    ],
    "correct": "Data privacy must be managed in accordance with the regulations applicable Io the organization."
  },
  {
    "question": "During an annual audit review, an IS auditor learns that a terminated employee's user account has remained in a critical system past the authorized time frame. Which of the following should the auditor do FIRST?",
    "options": [
      "Evaluate the controls for removing access.",
      "Increase the sample size of user accounts.",
      "Conduct additional access reviews",
      "Recommend that the user account be disabled."
    ],
    "correct": "Evaluate the controls for removing access."
  }
]
